[{"Date": "2020-07-06 15:13:33+00:00", "question": "In which Indian state longest 'canal' is situated?", "option1": "Bihar", "option2": "Jharkhand", "option3": "Rajasthan", "option4": "Uttar Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-29 05:36:53+00:00", "question": "Choose the incorrect statement about International Transport Forum (ITF) :", "option1": "It is\u00a0an\u00a0intergovernmental organisation\u00a0within OECD.", "option2": "It acts as a\u00a0think tank\u00a0for transport policy and organises\u00a0the Annual Summit of transport ministers.", "option3": "ITF is\u00a0the only global body that\u00a0covers all transport modes.", "option4": "The ITF is\u00a0administratively integrated with the OECD and\u00a0politically not autonomous.", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-29 05:35:30+00:00", "question": "According to sharda act, recent changes is done for minimum age of marriage for girl is?", "option1": "25 yr", "option2": "21 yr", "option3": "20 yr", "option4": "22 yr", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-29 05:12:18+00:00", "question": "Who was the first Indian to join Indian Civil Services?", "option1": "Romesh Dutt", "option2": "Satyendranath Tagore", "option3": "Behari Lal Gupta", "option4": "Anand Ram Baruah", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-27 17:38:50+00:00", "question": "'Kashmiri pandit' exodus started from which year?", "option1": "1998", "option2": "1990", "option3": "1999", "option4": "2000", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-27 17:30:36+00:00", "question": "The Human development index(HDI), development and applied for the first tym in?", "option1": "1996", "option2": "1990", "option3": "1975", "option4": "1972", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-27 17:26:41+00:00", "question": "The most populous country in South East asia is?", "option1": "Myanmar", "option2": "Laos", "option3": "Vietnam", "option4": "Indonesia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-24 15:19:29+00:00", "question": "The northern hemisphere\u2019s longest day of the year is called\u00a0the summer solstice.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-24 14:12:49+00:00", "question": "Is India a member of EAG(Eurasian Group on Combating Money Laundering and Financing of Terrorism) ?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-22 09:03:38+00:00", "question": "Yellow Journalism is used to denote \"fake news\".", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-19 02:37:58+00:00", "question": "World Meteorological Organization is a member of UNDP.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-19 02:30:50+00:00", "question": "National Rainfed Area Authority works under which Ministry?", "option1": "Rural Development", "option2": "Earth Sciences", "option3": "Human Resource Development", "option4": "Agriculture and Farmers Welfare", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-19 02:21:55+00:00", "question": "If 20% - 40% of India is affected by drought it is called a drought year.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-19 02:17:17+00:00", "question": "Warabandi is associated with", "option1": "Irrigation", "option2": "Fertilizer", "option3": "Land Distribution", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-19 01:54:32+00:00", "question": "Rythu bandu is a model associated with Indian Agriculture by the state of", "option1": "Maharashtra", "option2": "Gujarat", "option3": "Madhya Pradesh", "option4": "Telangana", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 08:39:05+00:00", "question": "The residuary powers in India are vested in the", "option1": "Union", "option2": "State", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 08:37:42+00:00", "question": "Indian Federalism has got similarities with", "option1": "Canada", "option2": "USA", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 08:37:00+00:00", "question": "Labour welfare comes under which list?", "option1": "Union", "option2": "State", "option3": "Concurrent", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-16 03:16:38+00:00", "question": "Raja Parba is festival of", "option1": "Bihar", "option2": "Jharkhand", "option3": "Orissa", "option4": "MP", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-16 01:06:15+00:00", "question": "World Day against Child Labour is observed on", "option1": "12th June", "option2": "16th June", "option3": "12th May", "option4": "16th May", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-16 00:56:25+00:00", "question": "National Cooperative Development Corporation (NCDC)\u00a0was established by an Act of Parliament in 1963 under\u00a0Ministry of Rural Development.\u00a0It has many regional centres to provide the financial assistance to Cooperatives/Societies/Federations.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-16 00:20:13+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0Kuno-Palpur Wildlife Sanctuary is in", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Uttar Pradesh", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "Orissa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-16 00:13:41+00:00", "question": "Norilsk recently seen in news, is in which country?", "option1": "New Zealand", "option2": "Thailand", "option3": "Russia", "option4": "Sri Lanka", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-15 23:27:35+00:00", "question": "IFLOWS initiative is by which state?", "option1": "West Bengal", "option2": "Orissa", "option3": "Tamil Nadu", "option4": "Maharashtra", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 10:58:58+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement:", "option1": "The Chalakudy River is\u00a0a tributary of the Periyar River.", "option2": "The Chalakudy Riveroriginates in the Anamalai region of Tamil Nadu.", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 09:27:02+00:00", "question": "Daporiji Bridge is over which river?", "option1": "Kaliganga", "option2": "Subansiri", "option3": "Alaknanda", "option4": "Kaveri", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 08:06:48+00:00", "question": "Ramon Magsaysay Award is\u00a0Asia\u2019s highest honour and is often regarded as the region\u2019s equivalent of the Nobel Prize. The award is named after president of which country?", "option1": "Malaysia", "option2": "Indonesia", "option3": "Philippines", "option4": "Vietnam", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 08:02:37+00:00", "question": "The Coral Triangle,\u00a0the world\u2019s epicentre of marine biodiversity, which encompasses\u00a0the seas of 6 countries in the Asia-Pacific region:\u00a0Indonesia, Malaysia, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Solomon Islands, and Timor Leste.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-12 02:41:23+00:00", "question": "Kishtwar National Park is in", "option1": "Ladakh", "option2": "Uttarakhand", "option3": "Jammu and Kashmir", "option4": "Sikkim", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-09 17:32:50+00:00", "question": "The Oil India Limited\u2019s (OIL) Baghjan gas well\u00a0is in tinsukia district. It is in which state?", "option1": "Sikkim", "option2": "Assam", "option3": "Andhra Pradesh", "option4": "Telangana", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 21:15:36+00:00", "question": "The Gulf Cooperation Council is India\u2019s largest regional-bloc trading partner.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 20:45:00+00:00", "question": "Sundarbans is\u00a0the 27th Ramsar Site in India,\u00a0and with an area of 4,23,000 hectares is now the largest protected wetland in the country.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 20:40:53+00:00", "question": "Central bureau of investigation (cbi) was set up in?", "option1": "1982", "option2": "1963", "option3": "1965", "option4": "1997", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 20:39:30+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0Ambarnaya river flows to the Pyasino lake and river Pyasina,\u00a0which connects it to\u00a0the Kara sea, a part of the Pacific Ocean.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 20:34:14+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement about Nagar Van Scheme -\n\n1) Under the scheme, around 200 urban forests are to be developed all over the country in the next five years. 2) The scheme will also provide an opportunity to the states to manage urban ecosystems.", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 20:14:06+00:00", "question": "A lot of chaos can be seen on the India-China border right now. Is China trying to divert India from the issue of PoK due to its CPEC project?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 23:54:40+00:00", "question": "Tripoli is", "option1": "The capital city of Libya", "option2": "The largest city in Libya", "option3": "Both A and B", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 23:17:04+00:00", "question": "It\u00a0is a program for\u00a0providing fresh graduates experiential learning opportunities in the urban sector.", "option1": "Udaan", "option2": "Tulip", "option3": "Fly", "option4": "Heights", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 23:07:18+00:00", "question": "Lynching incidents can be dealt with under Section 301 and 302 of IPC.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 22:38:15+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is true about Ameri Ice Shelf?", "option1": "It is one of the largest glacier drainage basins in the world, located on east coast of Antarctica.", "option2": "It is located at\u00a0head of Prydz Bay between the Lars Christensen Coast and Ingrid Christensen Coast.", "option3": "It is part of\u00a0Mac. Robertson Land.", "option4": "All of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 22:34:54+00:00", "question": "Which port is\u00a0the only riverine port in the country, situated 203 km from the sea?", "option1": "Vishakhapatnam", "option2": "Kochi", "option3": "Mumbai", "option4": "Kolkata", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 22:06:57+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0government of which country\u00a0has suspended plans to cancel\u00a0the Visiting Forces Agreement (VFA),\u00a0a deal that is important to Washington\u2019s moves to counter Beijing\u2019s rising regional power?", "option1": "Indonesia", "option2": "Malaysia", "option3": "Vietnam", "option4": "Phillipines", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 21:21:16+00:00", "question": "Should the name of our country be changed from \"India\" to \"Bharat\"?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 15:03:24+00:00", "question": "Under 'RTI' act, in how many days the information is provided to applicants?", "option1": "56 days", "option2": "60 days", "option3": "30 days", "option4": "15 days", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-05 02:31:24+00:00", "question": "Which one of the following is a Government Recipient?", "option1": "Income Recipient", "option2": "Capital Recipients", "option3": "Debt Recipients", "option4": "None of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-04 23:23:13+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0Cabinet Committee of Economic Affairs\u00a0announces MSP for various crops at the beginning of each sowing season based on the\u00a0recommendations of\u00a0the Commission for Agricultural Costs and Prices (CACP).\u00a0", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-04 17:07:57+00:00", "question": "Cyclone Nisarga is in", "option1": "Bay of Bengal", "option2": "Arabian Sea", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-04 16:37:27+00:00", "question": "RT-PCR is a type of", "option1": "Drug", "option2": "Pesticide", "option3": "Missile", "option4": "Test of a disease", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 16:37:23+00:00", "question": "Inter-State migration comes under which list?", "option1": "Union List", "option2": "State List", "option3": "Concurrent List", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 16:34:51+00:00", "question": "Makru River Bridge is in which state?", "option1": "Manipur", "option2": "Arunachal Pradesh", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "Assam", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 16:26:14+00:00", "question": "The Jiribam-Imphal railway line will connect which city to the rest of the India?", "option1": "Aizawl", "option2": "Imphal", "option3": "Gangtok", "option4": "Dispur", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-02 13:34:30+00:00", "question": "Afghanistan is majorly rich in?", "option1": "Oil", "option2": "Opium", "option3": "Sagar cane", "option4": "Dry fruits", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-01 15:24:16+00:00", "question": "AR500C is an unmanned helicopter of which country?", "option1": "Russia", "option2": "USA", "option3": "China", "option4": "India", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-01 15:22:36+00:00", "question": "Which plateau is the highest one in the world?", "option1": "The Deccan", "option2": "The Tibetan", "option3": "The Colorado", "option4": "The Laurentian", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-01 00:24:33+00:00", "question": "Which state has announced the launch of\u00a0the \u2018Rozgar Setu\u2019 scheme\u00a0to\u00a0help secure employment for skilled workers who have returned.", "option1": "Uttar Pradesh", "option2": "Madhya Pradesh", "option3": "Bihar", "option4": "Orissa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-31 20:51:06+00:00", "question": "Which state government will develop 800 km roads as Herbal roads in the state?", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Uttrakhand", "option3": "Kerala", "option4": "Uttar Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-30 20:35:24+00:00", "question": "Adriatic Sea borders the country of Montenegro.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-30 20:30:30+00:00", "question": "The New Development Bank is operated by", "option1": "ASEAN", "option2": "IBSA", "option3": "BRICS", "option4": "NATO", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-29 20:10:52+00:00", "question": "Additional Excise Duty is imposed and collected by", "option1": "State", "option2": "Centre", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-29 16:52:20+00:00", "question": "Abhinav Bharat Society was founded by", "option1": "B R Ambedkar", "option2": "Mahatma Gandhi", "option3": "Veer Savarkar", "option4": "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-28 22:36:06+00:00", "question": "#OpinionPoll\n\nIndian System of Governance is", "option1": "Fully Federal", "option2": "Quasi Federal", "option3": "Pseudo Federal", "option4": "Non Federal", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 20:58:02+00:00", "question": "National Development Council which was established by Government of India on the recommendations of the 1st Five Year Plans is", "option1": "A constitutional body", "option2": "A Statutory body", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 12:27:50+00:00", "question": "Dehing Patkai Wildlife Sanctuary is in", "option1": "Arunachal Pradesh", "option2": "Uttarakhand", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "Assam", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 12:26:26+00:00", "question": "Jubaland  is an autonomous region in", "option1": "Kenya", "option2": "Nigeria", "option3": "Niger", "option4": "Somalia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 11:55:31+00:00", "question": "Stubble burning results in emission of Nitrogen Dioxide.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 09:55:56+00:00", "question": "When a typical characteristics of a tropical cyclone are replaced  with those of extra tropical cyclone then it is called", "option1": "Semi Tropical", "option2": "Post Tropical", "option3": "Neo Tropical", "option4": "Pseudo Tropical", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 09:53:49+00:00", "question": "Cyclone Mangga, recently seen in news has hit which of the following?", "option1": "USA", "option2": "Australia", "option3": "India", "option4": "Phillipines", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-24 09:19:22+00:00", "question": "What is WAG-12 , recently seen in news?", "option1": "Locomotive Engine", "option2": "Submarine", "option3": "Aircraft", "option4": "Locomotive Tank", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-23 08:18:55+00:00", "question": "In Economics,  100 bps is equal to", "option1": "1%", "option2": "10%", "option3": "100%", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-23 08:15:11+00:00", "question": "If Repo Rate is X, then Reverse Repo Rate will be", "option1": "X", "option2": "X - 0.25", "option3": "X + 0.25", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-22 05:05:37+00:00", "question": "Blood thinners are given to prevent pulmonary embolism.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-22 04:11:56+00:00", "question": "'Open skies treaty' is about?", "option1": "Making good decisions in weapons exchange between country", "option2": "Keeping eyes on country on the movement of troops and other activities", "option3": "Transparency between the country about making of nuclear bomb", "option4": "Not selling of weapons to country who's ranking are less according to human rights", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-22 04:05:58+00:00", "question": "Which country recently withdraws itself from open skies treaty?", "option1": "China", "option2": "Russia", "option3": "India", "option4": "US", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-21 15:54:37+00:00", "question": "Troglomyces twitteri is a new species of", "option1": "Bacteria", "option2": "Fungus", "option3": "Virus", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-21 05:15:29+00:00", "question": "Which state pays the highest wage under MGNREGA Scheme?", "option1": "Maharashtra", "option2": "Gujarat", "option3": "Kerala", "option4": "Haryana", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 19:09:50+00:00", "question": "Which religion in Nepal has the highest majority?", "option1": "Hinduism", "option2": "Buddhism", "option3": "Islam", "option4": "Christianity", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 13:26:24+00:00", "question": "GOAL (Going Online As Leaders)\u201d programme launched by Ministry of Tribal Affairs in association with", "option1": "Google", "option2": "Instagram", "option3": "Facebook", "option4": "Tesla", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 13:17:56+00:00", "question": "Quinine Nongladew is", "option1": "A drug", "option2": "A place", "option3": "A satellite", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 13:07:46+00:00", "question": "Eventbot recently seen in news is", "option1": "A type of Ship", "option2": "An app", "option3": "A malware", "option4": "A missile", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 12:59:28+00:00", "question": "Global Economic Prospects is released by", "option1": "World Economic Forum", "option2": "World Bank", "option3": "United Nations", "option4": "Shanghai Cooperation Organization", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 12:58:17+00:00", "question": "NABARD is wholly owned by", "option1": "RBI", "option2": "Government of India", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 09:20:23+00:00", "question": "Dibang Multipurpose Project is in which state?", "option1": "Sikkim", "option2": "Bihar", "option3": "West Bengal", "option4": "Arunanchal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 08:55:32+00:00", "question": "The Shanghai Cooperation Organization's official language  is\n\n1) Russian 2) Chinese 3) Arabic", "option1": "Only 2", "option2": "Both 1 and 2", "option3": "All", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 08:30:26+00:00", "question": "Boko Haram emerged in", "option1": "Niger", "option2": "Nigeria", "option3": "Chad", "option4": "Cameroon", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 08:22:04+00:00", "question": "Indian Army is considering to allow common citizens to join the 1.3- million-strong force for a three-year tenure to serve the nation under\u00a0which scheme?", "option1": "Tour of Duty Scheme", "option2": "Three Years Short Service Scheme", "option3": "Both", "option4": "Only 2", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 08:18:28+00:00", "question": "The highest percentage of plantation forests is in", "option1": "Europe", "option2": "North America", "option3": "South America", "option4": "Australia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 04:52:25+00:00", "question": "The treaty of Sugauli was signed between India and?", "option1": "Pakistan", "option2": "Bangladesh", "option3": "China", "option4": "Nepal", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 04:30:35+00:00", "question": "Which European country declared an end to its covid 19 epidemic?", "option1": "Spain", "option2": "Slovenia", "option3": "Austria", "option4": "Luxembourg", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 04:16:42+00:00", "question": "Recently,in New map of Nepal which area is showcased the part of Nepal?", "option1": "Lipulekh", "option2": "Kalapani", "option3": "All of these", "option4": "Limpiyadhura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 04:10:05+00:00", "question": "Does India has to start talking with Taliban? What's ur opinion", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 09:11:45+00:00", "question": "Which cyclone is likely to develop in the Bay of Bengal recently?", "option1": "Fani", "option2": "Amphan", "option3": "Vayu", "option4": "Gati", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 05:50:08+00:00", "question": "Which state has got the highest GDP?", "option1": "Gujarat", "option2": "Karnataka", "option3": "Maharashtra", "option4": "Kerala", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 04:01:48+00:00", "question": "In India, the highest coal reserves is found in which state?", "option1": "Orissa", "option2": "Jharkhand", "option3": "MP", "option4": "Chattisgarh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 03:58:44+00:00", "question": "Coal liquefication is a process of converting coal into liquid hydrocarbons.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 03:51:51+00:00", "question": "India is at which rank in terms of coal resources in the world?", "option1": "1st", "option2": "2nd", "option3": "4th", "option4": "5th", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 03:19:40+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement  - \n\n1) Slovenia is a land locked country.  2) Italy shares border with Slovenia.", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-18 11:29:32+00:00", "question": "Which country is not a part of world health Assembly (WHA)?", "option1": "China", "option2": "Japan", "option3": "Taiwan", "option4": "India", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-18 11:11:09+00:00", "question": "The capital of Balochistan is", "option1": "Qwadar", "option2": "Muscat", "option3": "Tehran", "option4": "Quetta", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-18 10:52:43+00:00", "question": "The World Health Assembly is the key decision making assembly of which international organizations?", "option1": "EU", "option2": "WHO", "option3": "ASEAN", "option4": "UNFCCC", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-18 10:49:51+00:00", "question": "The uyghurs belong to mainly which country?", "option1": "Pakistan", "option2": "China", "option3": "Afganistan", "option4": "Bangladesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 03:58:35+00:00", "question": "Naku La is in", "option1": "Jammu and Kashmir", "option2": "Uttrakhand", "option3": "Arunachal Pradesh", "option4": "Sikkim", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-14 12:02:37+00:00", "question": "In Preferential Trade Agreement there is", "option1": "Negative list on which duties is not to be reduced", "option2": "Positive list on which duties is not to be reduced", "option3": "Negative list on which duties is to be reduced", "option4": "Positive list on which duties is to be reduced", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-14 07:47:35+00:00", "question": "WHA, World health Assembly headquarter is in?", "option1": "US", "option2": "China", "option3": "Taiwan", "option4": "Switzerland", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-14 01:48:10+00:00", "question": "Long March 5 - It is a rocket of which country?", "option1": "Russia", "option2": "Israel", "option3": "China", "option4": "Iran", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-14 01:47:24+00:00", "question": "Chunks of powerful rocket falls back to earth narrowly missing NY city. It belonged to which country?", "option1": "Iran", "option2": "North Korea", "option3": "Russia", "option4": "China", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-13 11:39:58+00:00", "question": "The Global Competitiveness Report is published by the", "option1": "IMF", "option2": "World Bank", "option3": "UN Conference on Trade and Commerce", "option4": "World Economic Forum", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-13 02:17:58+00:00", "question": "Asiatic Society of Bengal was established by", "option1": "N B Halhed", "option2": "Sir William Jones", "option3": "Max Mueller", "option4": "A L Basham", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 22:39:22+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is a command economy?", "option1": "South Korea", "option2": "North Korea", "option3": "India", "option4": "Norway", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 22:23:49+00:00", "question": "Mining and quarrying comes under which sector?", "option1": "Primary", "option2": "Secondary", "option3": "Tertiary", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 20:19:50+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is not a member of five eyes group?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "New Zealand", "option3": "Canada", "option4": "Russia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 20:17:51+00:00", "question": "Is India a member of World Health Assembly?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 09:19:05+00:00", "question": "Recently, Rbi has launched voluntary retention route to debts markets.. Its major objective is?", "option1": "Attracting long term and stable Fpi", "option2": "Attracting short term Fdi", "option3": "Making Fpi investment with no rules", "option4": "To maintain Fpi for atleast 5 years", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 09:09:29+00:00", "question": "Is relaxing some rules and regulations in a country, then it makes more investment or not?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 09:00:06+00:00", "question": "Equity market is not a share market. This statement is correct or not?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 08:58:26+00:00", "question": "Debt market is know as bond market. Is it true or not?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 08:22:48+00:00", "question": "The National institute of virology (NIV) in pune has developed and validated the indigenous igG elisa test for antibody detection of covid-19 namely?", "option1": "Covid care elisa", "option2": "Covid control elisa", "option3": "Covid kavach elisa", "option4": "Covid roktham elisa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 05:34:48+00:00", "question": "Which country will launch its first Arktika-M satellite\u00a0to monitor the Arctic climate and environment later this year?", "option1": "Israel", "option2": "Iran", "option3": "Russia", "option4": "US", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-12 02:25:19+00:00", "question": "The Andhra Pradesh government has decided to send back the remaining stock of styrene gas at the LG Polymers factory in Visakhapatnam to which country?", "option1": "Japan", "option2": "Russia", "option3": "Israel", "option4": "South Korea", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-11 19:17:29+00:00", "question": "What was previously\u00a010,000 rials will become one Toman under the plans. (Iran's currency change)", "option1": "True", "option2": "Flase", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-11 19:12:18+00:00", "question": "The world\u2019s leading data, insights and consulting company released its\u00a0ICUBE\u00a02019\u00a0report on digital adoption and usage trends in India. The name of the company is", "option1": "Quake", "option2": "Kantar", "option3": "Holbrook", "option4": "Vox", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-11 15:28:43+00:00", "question": "India- Nepal total border share is?", "option1": "1400 km", "option2": "1987 km", "option3": "690 km", "option4": "1690 km", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-11 09:51:15+00:00", "question": "Recently, india and china troops are involved in fierce face off near which psss?", "option1": "Nathu la pass", "option2": "Zo ji la pass", "option3": "Rohtang pass", "option4": "Naku la pass", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-10 16:17:44+00:00", "question": "Lipulekh\u00a0is a\u00a0Himalayan\u00a0pass\u00a0on the border between India's\u00a0Jammu and Kashmir\u00a0state and the\u00a0Tibet\u00a0region of China,\u00a0near their\u00a0trijunction\u00a0with\u00a0Nepal.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 10:08:06+00:00", "question": "Name of Iran latest currency is?", "option1": "Rial", "option2": "Toman", "option3": "Euro", "option4": "Peso", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 06:14:11+00:00", "question": "Recently, BRO has connected mansarovar Lake from Uttarakhand to which pass?", "option1": "Nathula pass", "option2": "Rohtang pass", "option3": "Lipulekh pass", "option4": "Bara lacha pass", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 06:08:27+00:00", "question": "How many routes are available to reach Mount Kailash from India?", "option1": "1", "option2": "5", "option3": "2", "option4": "4", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 06:00:02+00:00", "question": "Mount Kailash which is very famous for Indian pilgrims is situated in?", "option1": "Nepal", "option2": "China", "option3": "Bangladesh", "option4": "Srilanka", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 05:36:03+00:00", "question": "\"Nathula pass' is in which state?", "option1": "Himanchal pradesh", "option2": "Uttarakhand", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "West bengal", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-09 04:07:08+00:00", "question": "Recently, 15 pages dossier about covid-19 outbreak from wuhan laboratory is leaked by?", "option1": "ASEAN group", "option2": "Five Eyes group", "option3": "WHO", "option4": "Un  nations", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 15:50:11+00:00", "question": "Nordic countries are in?", "option1": "Southern Europe", "option2": "Northern Europe", "option3": "Africa", "option4": "Asia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 14:22:05+00:00", "question": "India meteorological department headquarter is situated in?", "option1": "Bangalore", "option2": "New Delhi", "option3": "Orissa", "option4": "Maharashtra", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 14:13:57+00:00", "question": "Which state was the first to set up happiness department?", "option1": "Kerala", "option2": "Goa", "option3": "Madhya Pradesh", "option4": "Himachal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 14:04:04+00:00", "question": "Rank of India in Social Progress Index (2019) is", "option1": "81", "option2": "96", "option3": "102", "option4": "117", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 04:29:59+00:00", "question": "To increase the growth rate, money supply should be", "option1": "Increased", "option2": "Decreased", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:34:31+00:00", "question": "Free Movement Regime is between India and which country?", "option1": "Nepal", "option2": "Bhutan", "option3": "Myanmar", "option4": "Sri Lanka", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:33:09+00:00", "question": "Male is the capital of", "option1": "Maldives", "option2": "Thailand", "option3": "Cambodia", "option4": "Laos", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:31:41+00:00", "question": "Atoll is a type of coral reefs.", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:30:39+00:00", "question": "Addu Atoll is present in which of the following ocean?", "option1": "Pacific", "option2": "Atlantic", "option3": "Indian", "option4": "Arctic", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:28:22+00:00", "question": "India signed MoUs to develop Trincomalee Port which is situated in", "option1": "Myanmar", "option2": "Sri Lanka", "option3": "Maldives", "option4": "Thailand", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:25:12+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement regarding Wagah-Attari border.\n\n1) Wagah is in Punjab 2) Attari is in Pakistan", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:20:59+00:00", "question": "India recently inaugurated 2nd Integrated Check Post at Jogbani (Bihar) and Biratnagar, which is in", "option1": "West Bengal", "option2": "Nepal", "option3": "Assam", "option4": "Bhutan", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:18:26+00:00", "question": "Motihari-Amlekhgunj Oil Pipeline is 69 km long, being first trans-national petroleum pipeline between India and", "option1": "Bhutan", "option2": "Nepal", "option3": "Myanmar", "option4": "Bangladesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:13:03+00:00", "question": "India has got 4 Central Armed Police Forces - \n\n1) CISF 2) CRPF 3) ITBP 4) BSF", "option1": "True", "option2": "False", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:06:08+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement - \n\n1) China shares 1140 km long boundary with India in Eastern Sector. 2) Line of actual control is between India and China one western side.", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 02:00:32+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement -\n\n1) Mamallapuram is a World Heritage Site. 2) Mamallapuram is in Tamil Nadu.", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-08 01:55:55+00:00", "question": "Choose the correct statement -\n\n1) China is India's largest trading partner. 2) China has got trade surplus of more than $50 billion USD with India.", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 19:44:55+00:00", "question": "Ambedkar's re-interpretation of Buddhism was called", "option1": "Navayana", "option2": "Dalit Buddhist Movement", "option3": "Neo-Buddhism", "option4": "All", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 19:38:32+00:00", "question": "B. R. Ambedkar converted into which religion from Hinduism?", "option1": "Jainism", "option2": "Buddhism", "option3": "Jews", "option4": "Didn't change", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 19:36:02+00:00", "question": "Under the Seventh Schedule of the Constitution of India, there are three lists \u2013 the Union, State and Concurrent. Which of the three has highest number of entries?", "option1": "Union", "option2": "State", "option3": "Concurrent", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 18:18:48+00:00", "question": "India bought \"INS Jalashwa\" from", "option1": "Israel", "option2": "Japan", "option3": "China", "option4": "US", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 15:56:15+00:00", "question": "Which gas leaked from LG Polymer Plant located in Andhra Pradesh?", "option1": "Styrene", "option2": "Acrylonitrile", "option3": "Carbon Monoxide", "option4": "Sulphur Dioxide", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 15:45:57+00:00", "question": "Netanyahu gets Supreme Court's nod to form Government, it led to end of political crisis of which country?", "option1": "Saudi Arabia", "option2": "Israel", "option3": "Yemen", "option4": "Syria", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 07:39:54+00:00", "question": "Which one of the following observations is not true about the Quit India Movement of 1942?", "option1": "It was a non-violent movement", "option2": "It was led by Mahatma Gandhi", "option3": "It was a spontaneous movement", "option4": "It did not attract the labour class in general", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 07:37:24+00:00", "question": "The Jain philosophy holds that the world is created and maintained by", "option1": "Universal Law", "option2": "Universal Truth", "option3": "Universal Faith", "option4": "Universal Soul", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-07 07:35:48+00:00", "question": "The religion of early Vedic Aryans was primarily of", "option1": "Bhakti", "option2": "image worship and Yajnas", "option3": "worship of nature and Yajnas", "option4": "worship of nature and Bhakti", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-26 07:06:41+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nIndependent candidates have been contesting in Lok Sabha elections since the first general election of 1951-52", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-26 07:03:54+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nAmchang Wildlife Sanctuary sometimes seen in news recently, is located in Mizoram", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-26 07:00:50+00:00", "question": "#IO\n\nInternational Finance Corporation (IFC) is the largest global development institution focused exclusively on the private sector in developing countries", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-23 07:04:31+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nContempt of court can either be civil contempt or criminal contempt", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-23 07:01:10+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nWith reference to the Parliament of India, which of the following Parliamentary committees is engaging in maintaining discipline and decorum in Parliament?", "option1": "Rules Committee", "option2": "Committee of Privileges", "option3": "Ethics Committee", "option4": "General Purposes Committee", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-23 06:57:54+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nPradhan Mantri Jan Arogya Yojana (PM-JAY) will cover medical and hospitalization expenses for almost all primary,secondary and tertiary care procedures", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-21 07:32:04+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nAirports Authority of India (AAI) was constituted by an Act of Parliament", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-21 07:28:56+00:00", "question": "#History\n\n\u201cPhanigiri\u201d is a Buddhist site located in Bihar", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-21 07:26:45+00:00", "question": "#IR\n\nShanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) is a permanent intergovernmental international organisation comprises of seven member states", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-20 06:07:18+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nGoldman Environmental Prize has been awarded annually by the UN Environment", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-20 06:05:25+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nNational Crisis Management Committee (NCMC) is headed by the Prime Minister", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-20 05:59:51+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nManjira Wildlife Sanctuary is located in Andhra Pradesh", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 07:43:45+00:00", "question": "#IR\n\nIndia is a signatory to the Arms Trade Treaty, 2013 of United Nations.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 07:39:42+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nShigellosis is a contagious disease caused by Shigella Virus.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-18 07:37:27+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nThe Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) are universal and apply to all countries, whereas the MDGs were intended for action in developing countries only", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-17 14:37:43+00:00", "question": "#Reports\n\nGlobal Food Policy Report is published by Food and Agricultural Organisation", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-17 06:45:33+00:00", "question": "#Culture\n\nKelchawa Festival is celebrated at the close of the harvest season by Tiwa tribes in the state of Assam", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-15 07:02:34+00:00", "question": "#Report\n\nGlobal Democracy Index is published annually by Transparency International", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-15 07:00:18+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nOperation Epervier II sometimes seen in the news recently is associated World Wildlife Fund", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-15 06:48:05+00:00", "question": "#Economy\n\nRepo rate is also applicable for Non-Banking Financial Companies", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-14 06:46:11+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nIt is a non-bailable offence and a person charged under the Sedition Law (Section 124A) is barred from a government job, have to live without passport", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-14 06:40:39+00:00", "question": "#Geography\n\nNational Centre for Seismology is responsible for classifying India into different seismic zones.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-14 06:37:24+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nSahakar Mitra Scheme is an initiative of National Cooperative Development Corporation (NCDC) launched by the Ministry of Agriculture & Farmers Welfare", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 13:59:42+00:00", "question": "#Culture\n\nJamdani is a muslin textile typically woven using a mixture of cotton and gold threads", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 13:53:06+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nWhich of the following are categorized as the \u2018Natural\u2019 UNESCO World Heritage Site in India? 1. Ajanta Caves 2. Kaziranga National Park 3. Keibul Lamjao National Park 4. Western Ghats Select the correct answer using the code given below", "option1": "2, 3 and 4 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "2 and 4 only", "option4": "1, 2 and 3 only", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-13 13:46:49+00:00", "question": "#Terms\n\nThe term 'Dtrack' sometimes seen in the news, is a", "option1": "Platform launched to track disaster frequencyin a district", "option2": "Malicious software or a malware", "option3": "Application launched to track dietary habits", "option4": "Anti-piracy software for music downloads", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-12 15:54:18+00:00", "question": "#History\n\nWith reference to medieval history of India, the term 'sadr' refers to military commanders", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-12 15:51:46+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nAtal Bimit Vyakti Kalyan Yojna was launched by Ministry of Labour and Employment", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-11 08:53:11+00:00", "question": "#History\n\nWith reference to Rigveda, the Rajas did not have capital cities, palaces or armies, nor did they collect taxes.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-09 15:44:50+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nNational Bamboo Mission (NBM) comes under the Ministry of Agriculture and Farmers Welfare", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-09 14:58:13+00:00", "question": "#Index\n\nGender Parity Index (GPI) is released by World Economic Forum", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-09 07:26:46+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nCan you answer this?  An animal describes itself as, 1.I am national animal of one of the South Asian countries. 2.I am an animal of higher altitude. 3.National animal of one of the South Asian countries is my main prey. The animal is,", "option1": "Markhor", "option2": "Snow leopard", "option3": "Tiger", "option4": "Leopard", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 09:36:26+00:00", "question": "#Culture\n\nGohain Uliuwa mela sometimes seen in news recently, is a festival celebrated in Manipur", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 09:32:00+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nMonuments are declared protected and of national importance by the National Monument Authority (NMA)", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-08 07:40:35+00:00", "question": "#Environment\nCan you answer this?\nOnce an animal was explaining about his native place in India. It says, 1.A biosphere reserve. 2.A hilly terrain. 3.Named from the name of a flower which blossoms in every 12 yrs. The hills it is talking about is,", "option1": "Kanchenjunga", "option2": "Nilgiri", "option3": "Nanda Devi", "option4": "Agasthyamala", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 07:00:15+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nTrade Records Analysis of Fauna and Flora in Commerce (TRAFFIC) is an organisation established by United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 06:51:20+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nProject 15 Bravo sometimes seen in the news recently is associated with Stealth Submarines", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-07 06:44:15+00:00", "question": "#Tribes\n\nChenchu Tribal Community sometimes seen in news recently, mainly lives in Arunachal Pradesh", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-06 14:13:17+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nBamako Convention sometimes seen in news recently is associated with peat land Conservation", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-06 06:50:14+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nCan you answer this?   Once a boy has visited a tiger reserve of terai region on India. After coming back to school he says to his friends, \"I have seen rhinoceros and swamp deer in a jungle safari.\" the tiger reserve he visited is,", "option1": "Dudhwa", "option2": "Valmiki", "option3": "Corbett", "option4": "Rajaji", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 09:13:15+00:00", "question": "#History\n\nJainism did not condemn the Varna system, as Buddhism.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 09:11:09+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nA Central Monitoring Committee to check river pollution was recently established by Central Pollution Control Board", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-03 09:07:45+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nExport Promotion Council for Handicrafts (EPCH) functions under the aegis of Ministry of Commerce and Industries.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-02 15:03:37+00:00", "question": "#History\n\nThere is no evidence of slavery during Mauryan period", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-02 14:57:15+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nMeasles is a human disease but also known to occur in animals", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-06-02 14:53:57+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nEnvironment Protection Act (EPA) 1986 mandates all local bodies to setup Biodiversity Management Committees (BMC)", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-31 13:41:57+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nBhadra Tiger Reserve sometimes seen in news recently is located in Jharkhand", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-31 13:38:16+00:00", "question": "#Misc\n\nUmbrella Revolution sometimes seen in the news, is associated with China-Taiwan Conflict", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-31 13:35:03+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nAZURE Mission sometimes seen in the news recently is associated with Gravitational Lensing", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incoorect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-30 08:59:56+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nStree Swabhiman Scheme comes under the Ministry of Women and Child Development.", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-30 08:55:41+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nSolar e-waste contains potentially hazardous elements like chromium, silicon tetrachloride, cadmium, and uranium", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-30 08:52:49+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nA person out on bail is allowed to cast his vote", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-29 07:35:37+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nPradhan Mantri Khanij Kshetra Kalyan Yojana was launched by the Ministry of Mines", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-29 07:12:02+00:00", "question": "#Polity\n\nPress Council of India (PCI) is a statutory and quasi-judicial body", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-29 06:59:03+00:00", "question": "Menhir, Cairn, Dolmen and Cist sometimes seen in the news refers to Age old stones", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-28 06:25:38+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nAchanakmar Wildlife Sanctuary sometimes seen in news recently is located in Kerala", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-28 06:20:04+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nProject Kuiper sometimes seen in the news recently is an initiative of Google", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-28 06:15:24+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nFAME India II Scheme is by the Ministry of Heavy Industries and Public Enterprises", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 06:12:37+00:00", "question": "#Geography\n\nTalcher city is India\u2019s largest coalfield located in Jharkhand", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 06:09:01+00:00", "question": "#History\n\nThere were no Indian members in the Hunter Committee of Inquiry, 1919", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-27 06:03:58+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nHope Mars Mission is a space exploration probe mission built by the NASA", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-26 06:23:13+00:00", "question": "#S&T\n\nCandida Auris sometimes seen in the news recently refers to phenomenon of bending of light rays by gravity", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-26 06:20:43+00:00", "question": "#Environment\n\nDandeli wildlife sanctuary is located in Madhya Pradesh", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-26 06:15:53+00:00", "question": "#Schemes\n\nPradhan Mantri Ujjwala Yojana (PMUY) was launched by the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare", "option1": "Correct", "option2": "Incorrect", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:22+00:00", "question": "Meja Dam is situated in which of the following state?\n\u092e\u0947\u091c\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Uttar Pradesh", "option2": "Madhya Pradesh", "option3": "Rajasthan", "option4": "Gujarat", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:22+00:00", "question": "On which of the following river Tilaiya Dam is situated?\n\u0924\u093f\u0932\u0948\u092f\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mayurakshi River", "option2": "Subarnarekha River", "option3": "Mahanadi River", "option4": "Barakar River", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:22+00:00", "question": "Tehri Dam is situated at the confluence of which two rivers?\n\u091f\u093f\u0939\u0930\u0940 \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0915\u093f\u0928 \u0926\u094b \u0928\u0926\u093f\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u092e \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Bhagirathi & Bhilanagana", "option2": "Bhagirathi & Alaknanda", "option3": "Alaknanda & Pindar", "option4": "Bhagirathi & Ghaghara", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:22+00:00", "question": "'Thein Dam' is situated on the river of\n'\u0925\u0940\u0928 \u0921\u0948\u092e' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Jhelum", "option2": "Ravi", "option3": "Chenab", "option4": "Satluj", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:22+00:00", "question": "Which one of the following dam is not situated on the river Chenab?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u091a\u093f\u0928\u093e\u092c \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0928\u0939\u0940\u0902 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Dul Hasti Dam", "option2": "Baglihar Dam", "option3": "Mangla Dam", "option4": "Salal Dam", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:33:50+00:00", "question": "The example of famous 'Charbagh gardens' in India is\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0938\u093f\u0926\u094d\u0927 '\u091a\u093e\u0930\u092c\u093e\u0917 \u0909\u0926\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u093e\u0939\u0930\u0923 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Rashtrapati Bhavan garden", "option2": "Shalimar Bagh\u00a0", "option3": "Taj Mahal", "option4": "National War Memorial in New Delhi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:33:50+00:00", "question": "Who is the only US president who have visited India twice while in office?\n\u0935\u0939 \u090f\u0915\u092e\u093e\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u0905\u092e\u0947\u0930\u093f\u0915\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u092a\u0924\u093f \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u0948 \u091c\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u092a\u0926 \u092a\u0930 \u0930\u0939\u0924\u0947 \u0939\u0941\u090f \u0926\u094b \u092c\u093e\u0930 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u093e \u0926\u094c\u0930\u093e \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Bill Clinton", "option2": "George Bush Junior", "option3": "Barack Obama", "option4": "Donald Trump", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:33:50+00:00", "question": "PM- Kisan (Kisan Samman Nidhi) Yojana effective from\n\u092a\u0940\u090f\u092e- \u0915\u093f\u0938\u093e\u0928 (\u0915\u093f\u0938\u093e\u0928 \u0938\u092e\u094d\u092e\u093e\u0928 \u0928\u093f\u0927\u0940) \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0915\u092c \u0938\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u092d\u093e\u0935\u0940", "option1": "01.01.2020", "option2": "01.12.2019", "option3": "01.12.2018", "option4": "05.05.2017", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:33:50+00:00", "question": "The stone chariot shrine at Hampi dedicated to whom?\n\u0939\u092e\u094d\u092a\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0925\u0930 \u0915\u093e \u0930\u0925 \u092e\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u094b \u0938\u092e\u0930\u094d\u092a\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Vishnu", "option2": "Garuda", "option3": "Mouse", "option4": "Shiva", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 13:12:26+00:00", "question": "Sardar Patel stadium is now the world's largest cricket stadium. What is its seating capacity?\n\u0938\u0930\u0926\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u091f\u0947\u0932 \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u0921\u093f\u092f\u092e \u0905\u092c \u0926\u0941\u0928\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0915\u094d\u0930\u093f\u0915\u0947\u091f \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u0921\u093f\u092f\u092e \u0939\u0948\u0964 \u0907\u0938\u0915\u0940 \u092c\u0948\u0920\u0928\u0947 \u0915\u0940 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u092e\u0924\u093e \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "90,000", "option2": "110,000", "option3": "130,000", "option4": "150,000", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:31+00:00", "question": "Which is the largest bay in the world in terms of area?\n\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930\u092b\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0926\u0943\u0937\u094d\u091f\u093f \u0938\u0947 \u0935\u093f\u0936\u094d\u0935 \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u0940 \u0916\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Hudson Bay", "option2": "San Francisco Bay", "option3": "Bay of Bengal", "option4": "Bay of Fundy", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:31+00:00", "question": "Boeing P-8 Poseidon aircraft is used for\n\u092c\u094b\u0907\u0902\u0917 \u092a\u0940 -8 \u092a\u094b\u0938\u093f\u0921\u0949\u0928 \u0935\u093f\u092e\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0907\u0938\u094d\u0924\u0947\u092e\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Anti Piracy", "option2": "Anti submarine warfare", "option3": "Heavy lift operations", "option4": "Rescue operation in disaster management", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:31+00:00", "question": "Who was referred to as Kerala Gandhi?\n\u0915\u0947\u0930\u0932 \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0927\u0940 \u0915\u0947 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0926\u0930\u094d\u092d\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Moyarath Sankaran", "option2": "Koyapalli Kelappan Nair", "option3": "K.R. Narayanan", "option4": "Mohammed Abdul Rahiman", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:31+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is known as India's easternmost tiger reserve?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0947 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092a\u0942\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0940 \u092c\u093e\u0918 \u0905\u092d\u092f\u093e\u0930\u0923\u094d\u092f \u0915\u0939\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Pakke Tiger Reserve", "option2": "Kamlang Tiger Reserve", "option3": "Nameri tiger reserve", "option4": "Namdapha Tiger Reserve", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:31+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is the northernmost city of Afghanistan?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0905\u092b\u0917\u093e\u0928\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u0924\u0930\u0940 \u0936\u0939\u0930 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mazari Sharif", "option2": "Kabul", "option3": "Jalalabad", "option4": "Kandahar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:49+00:00", "question": "Geological Survey of India\u00a0(GSI) was founded in the year\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u092d\u0942\u0935\u0948\u091c\u094d\u091e\u093e\u0928\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 (\u091c\u0940\u090f\u0938\u0906\u0908) \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093e\u092a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "1851", "option2": "1898", "option3": "1951", "option4": "1995", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:49+00:00", "question": "In which of the following national park five Rhinos were died from Suspected Anthrax Infection?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0909\u0926\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0928 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0917\u094d\u0927 \u090f\u0928\u094d\u0925\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0915\u094d\u0938 \u0938\u0902\u0915\u094d\u0930\u092e\u0923 \u0938\u0947 \u092a\u093e\u0902\u091a \u0917\u0948\u0902\u0921\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u092e\u0943\u0924\u094d\u092f\u0941 \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Kaziranga National Park", "option2": "Jaldapara National Park", "option3": "Orang National Park", "option4": "Manas National Park", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:49+00:00", "question": "Yakshagana is a\u00a0traditional theatre\u00a0form of\u00a0which state?\n\u092f\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0917\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0915\u093e \u092a\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092a\u0930\u093f\u0915 \u0930\u0902\u0917\u092e\u0902\u091a \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Tamil Nadu", "option2": "Kerala", "option3": "Karnataka", "option4": "Andhra Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:49+00:00", "question": "What is the IUCN Status\u00a0of\u00a0Hilsa fish?\n\u0939\u093f\u0932\u0938\u093e \u092e\u091b\u0932\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0906\u0908\u092f\u0942\u0938\u0940\u090f\u0928 \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u091f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Extinct- \u0935\u093f\u0932\u0941\u092a\u094d\u0924", "option2": "Threatened Species \u0916\u0924\u0930\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902", "option3": "Near-threatened \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 \u092a\u0930 \u0928\u093f\u0930\u094d\u092d\u0930", "option4": "Least Concern \u0916\u0924\u0930\u0947 \u0938\u0947 \u092c\u093e\u0939\u0930", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:49+00:00", "question": "Which is the largest protected\u00a0wetland\u00a0of the country?\n\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093f\u0924 \u0906\u0930\u094d\u0926\u094d\u0930\u092d\u0942\u092e\u093f \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ashtamudi Wetland", "option2": "East Kolkata Wetland", "option3": "Keoladeo National Park", "option4": "Sundarban Wetland", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:59+00:00", "question": "India contributes what percentage of the global biodiversity?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u091c\u0948\u0935 \u0935\u093f\u0935\u093f\u0927\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0924\u0928\u093e \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0924\u093f\u0936\u0924 \u092f\u094b\u0917\u0926\u093e\u0928 \u0926\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "4%", "option2": "8%", "option3": "12%", "option4": "14%", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:59+00:00", "question": "The Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species (CMS) or the Bonn Convention was signed on\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0935\u093e\u0938\u0940 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u091c\u093e\u0924\u093f \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 (\u0938\u0940\u090f\u092e\u090f\u0938) \u092f\u093e \u092c\u0949\u0928 \u0915\u0928\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u0936\u0928 \u092a\u0930 \u0915\u0928\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u0936\u0928 \u092a\u0930 \u0939\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u090f \u0917\u090f \u0925\u0947", "option1": "1975", "option2": "1979", "option3": "1983", "option4": "1987", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:59+00:00", "question": "'Sri Rama Sagar Project' is situated on the river of\n'\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u092e \u0938\u093e\u0917\u0930 \u092a\u0930\u093f\u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Godavari", "option2": "Krishna", "option3": "Mahanadi", "option4": "Narmada", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:58+00:00", "question": "Kadam River is a tributary of\n\u0915\u0926\u092e \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0938\u0939\u093e\u092f\u0915 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Godavari", "option2": "Krishna", "option3": "Mahanadi", "option4": "Kaveri", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:58+00:00", "question": "Kawal Tiger Reserve\u00a0is\u00a0situated in which of the following state?\n\u0915\u0935\u093e\u0932 \u091f\u093e\u0907\u0917\u0930 \u0930\u093f\u091c\u0930\u094d\u0935 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Odisha", "option3": "Telangana", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:30+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0National Social Assistance Programme\u00a0(NSAP) was launched on\n\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0938\u093e\u092e\u093e\u091c\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0939\u093e\u092f\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e\u0930\u094d\u092f\u0915\u094d\u0930\u092e (NSAP) \u0915\u093e \u0936\u0941\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092d \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e", "option1": "1990", "option2": "1993", "option3": "1995", "option4": "1999", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:30+00:00", "question": "The provisions of the sixth schedule of Indian Constitution are applicable in which of the following states?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0938\u0902\u0935\u093f\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u0940 \u091b\u0920\u0940 \u0905\u0928\u0941\u0938\u0942\u091a\u0940 \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0935\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0932\u093e\u0917\u0942 \u0939\u094b\u0924\u0947 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Assam", "option2": "Nagaland", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "Manipur", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:30+00:00", "question": "The first National Panchayati Raj Day was observed on\n\u092a\u0939\u0932\u093e \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092a\u0902\u091a\u093e\u092f\u0924\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u091c \u0926\u093f\u0935\u0938 \u092e\u0928\u093e\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e", "option1": "24 April 2010", "option2": "24 April 2012", "option3": "24 April 2014", "option4": "24 April 2016", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:30+00:00", "question": "Who is the head of the Prime Minister's Office\u00a0(PMO)?\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u093e\u0930\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0932\u092f (PMO) \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u092e\u0941\u0916 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u094b\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Cabinet Secretary", "option2": "Principal Secretary", "option3": "Defence Secretary", "option4": "Prime Minister", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:30+00:00", "question": "Who was the first\u00a0Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG) of India?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u0939\u0932\u0947 \u0928\u093f\u092f\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0915 \u0914\u0930 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0932\u0947\u0916\u093e \u092a\u0930\u0940\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0915 (CAG) \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0925\u0947?", "option1": "Rajiv Mehrishi", "option2": "S. Ranganathan", "option3": "A. K. Chanda", "option4": "V. Narahari Rao", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:35:12+00:00", "question": "Which of the following article deals with the pardoning power of the governor?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0905\u0928\u0941\u091a\u094d\u091b\u0947\u0926 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u092e\u093e \u0936\u0915\u094d\u0924\u093f \u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Article 160", "option2": "Article 161", "option3": "Article 165", "option4": "Article 172", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:35:12+00:00", "question": "Which of the following article defines that it is our fundamental duty to protect and improve the natural environment including forests, lakes, rivers and wild life?\n\u0928\u0926\u093f\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u0914\u0930 \u0935\u0928\u094d\u092f \u091c\u0940\u0935\u0928 \u0938\u0939\u093f\u0924 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0915\u0943\u0924\u093f\u0915 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0935\u0930\u0923 \u0915\u0940 \u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u0914\u0930 \u0938\u0941\u0927\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0930\u0928\u093e \u0939\u092e\u093e\u0930\u093e \u092e\u094c\u0932\u093f\u0915 \u0915\u0930\u094d\u0924\u0935\u094d\u092f \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Article 51A(c)\u00a0", "option2": "Article 51A(e)", "option3": "Article 51A(f)\u00a0", "option4": "Article 51A(g)", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:35:12+00:00", "question": "What was the strength of judges in Constitution bench\u00a0of the Supreme Court\u00a0in the famous Kesavananda Bharati\u00a0judgement?\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0938\u093f\u0926\u094d\u0927 \u0915\u0947\u0938\u0935\u093e\u0928\u0902\u0926 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940 \u092b\u0948\u0938\u0932\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u094b\u091a\u094d\u091a \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093e\u0932\u092f \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u0902\u0935\u093f\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u092a\u0940\u0920 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093e\u0927\u0940\u0936\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u0902\u0916\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "09", "option2": "11", "option3": "13", "option4": "15", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:35:12+00:00", "question": "In which of the following state 'Angami' tribe is found?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 '\u0905\u0902\u0917\u093e\u092e\u0940' \u091c\u0928\u091c\u093e\u0924\u093f \u092a\u093e\u0908 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Meghalaya", "option2": "Nagaland", "option3": "Assam", "option4": "West Bengal", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:35:11+00:00", "question": "In which of the following regions 'Santa Ana' winds flow?\n'\u0938\u093e\u0902\u0924\u093e \u090f\u0928\u093e' \u0939\u0935\u093e\u090f\u0901 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092c\u0939\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "California", "option2": "Japan", "option3": "Sudan", "option4": "Germany", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:58+00:00", "question": "'Matorral vegetation' is found in which of the following region?\n'\u092e\u0947\u0915\u094d\u091f\u094b\u0930\u0932 \u0935\u0928\u0938\u094d\u092a\u0924\u093f \u2019\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u093e\u0908 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mediterranean coast", "option2": "South Indian coast", "option3": "Chile", "option4": "Mexico", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:58+00:00", "question": "'Chaparral tea' is found in which of the following region?\n'\u091b\u093e\u092a\u0930\u093e\u0932 \u091a\u093e\u092f\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u093e\u092f\u0940 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "South Africa", "option2": "India", "option3": "Argentina", "option4": "California", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:58+00:00", "question": "Which ridge is called as Dolphin Ridge?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093f\u091c \u0915\u094b \u0921\u0949\u0932\u094d\u092b\u093f\u0928 \u0930\u093f\u091c \u0915\u0939\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Indian Ocean ridge", "option2": "Mid Atlantic ridge", "option3": "South Atlantic ridge", "option4": "None of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:58+00:00", "question": "'Karnapura' coal field is situated in which of the following river valley?\n'\u0915\u0930\u094d\u0928\u093e\u092a\u0941\u0930\u093e' \u0915\u094b\u092f\u0932\u093e \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0918\u093e\u091f\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Son Valley", "option2": "Damodar Valley", "option3": "Godavari Valley", "option4": "Mahanadi Valley", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:57+00:00", "question": "Which of the following rivers passes through Jim Corbett National Park?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u0940 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u091c\u093f\u092e \u0915\u0949\u0930\u094d\u092c\u0947\u091f \u0928\u0947\u0936\u0928\u0932 \u092a\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0915 \u0938\u0947 \u0939\u094b\u0915\u0930 \u0917\u0941\u091c\u0930\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mandakini river", "option2": "Pindar river", "option3": "Ramganga river", "option4": "Dhauliganga river", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:24+00:00", "question": "The 'Loess Plateau' is situated in which of the following country?\n'\u0932\u094b\u090f\u0938 \u092a\u0920\u093e\u0930' \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0926\u0947\u0936 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mongolia", "option2": "China", "option3": "Vietnam", "option4": "Myanmar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:24+00:00", "question": "Which department monitors earthquakes and conducts seismological research?\n\u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0935\u093f\u092d\u093e\u0917 \u092d\u0942\u0915\u0902\u092a \u0915\u0940 \u0928\u093f\u0917\u0930\u093e\u0928\u0940 \u0914\u0930 \u092d\u0942\u0915\u0902\u092a\u0940\u092f \u0905\u0928\u0941\u0938\u0902\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u0930\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "National Centre for Seismology", "option2": "Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology", "option3": "National Center for Earth System Sciences", "option4": "Indian Tsunami Early Warning Centre", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:24+00:00", "question": "'Achanakmar Wildlife Sanctuary'\u00a0is situated in which of the following state?\n'\u0905\u091a\u0928\u0915\u092e\u093e\u0930 \u0935\u0928\u094d\u092f\u091c\u0940\u0935 \u0905\u092d\u092f\u093e\u0930\u0923\u094d\u092f\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Bihar", "option3": "Chhattisgarh", "option4": "Himachal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:24+00:00", "question": "How many states are the Satpura hills spread?\n\u0938\u0924\u092a\u0941\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u092a\u0939\u093e\u0921\u093c\u093f\u092f\u093e\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0924\u0928\u0947 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092b\u0948\u0932\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "3", "option2": "4", "option3": "5", "option4": "2", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:24+00:00", "question": "'Moribund delta' is a subdivision of which of the following delta?\n'\u092e\u094b\u0930\u093f\u092c\u0902\u0921 \u0921\u0947\u0932\u094d\u091f\u093e' \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0921\u0947\u0932\u094d\u091f\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0909\u092a\u0916\u0902\u0921 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Krishna Godavari delta", "option2": "Mahanadi delta", "option3": "Bengal delta", "option4": "Cauvery delta", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:20:16+00:00", "question": "The Indian National Army (INA) Defence Committee which was constituted in the year 1945 headed by whom?\n\u0906\u091c\u093e\u0926 \u0939\u093f\u0902\u0926 \u092b\u094c\u091c (INA) \u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u0938\u092e\u093f\u0924\u093f \u0915\u093e \u0917\u0920\u0928 1945 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0928\u0947\u0924\u0943\u0924\u094d\u0935 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Asaf Ali", "option2": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "option3": "Bhulabhai Desai", "option4": "Rajendra Prasad", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:20:16+00:00", "question": "Poona Pact was signed in between whom?\n\u092a\u0942\u0928\u093e \u092a\u0948\u0915\u094d\u091f \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u0939\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0930\u093f\u0924 \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Gandhi & Ambedkr", "option2": "MM Malviya & Ambedkar", "option3": "Gandhi & MM Malviya", "option4": "Ambedkar & Lord Willington", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:20:16+00:00", "question": "Which of the following movement was led by Madari Pasi?\n\u092e\u0926\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u092a\u093e\u0938\u0940 \u0928\u0947 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0906\u0902\u0926\u094b\u0932\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0928\u0947\u0924\u0943\u0924\u094d\u0935 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Pabna", "option2": "Santhal", "option3": "Eka", "option4": "Tana Bhagat", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:20:16+00:00", "question": "'Battle of Jajau' (battle of succession of Aurangzeb) was fought in which of the following year?\n'\u091c\u093e\u091c\u090a \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908' (\u0914\u0930\u0902\u0917\u091c\u0947\u092c \u0915\u0947 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u0924\u0930\u093e\u0927\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908) \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "1706", "option2": "1707", "option3": "1708", "option4": "1710", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:20:15+00:00", "question": "Between whom the\u00a0battle of Dharmat\u00a0was fought?\n\u0927\u0930\u094d\u092e\u0924 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Jalal Khan & Banda Singh Bahadur", "option2": "Maratha empire & Mughal empire", "option3": "Aurangzeb & Sambhaji", "option4": "Dara Shikoh & Aurangzeb", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 14:43:14+00:00", "question": "Who was the\u00a0last\u00a0king of the\u00a0Pallava\u00a0dynasty?\n\u092a\u0932\u094d\u0932\u0935 \u0935\u0902\u0936 \u0915\u093e \u0905\u0902\u0924\u093f\u092e \u0930\u093e\u091c\u093e \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Aparajitavarman", "option2": "Dantivarman", "option3": "Mahendravarman II", "option4": "Nandivarman III", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 14:43:14+00:00", "question": "Who is the author of 'Tabaqat-i-Nasiri'?\n'\u0924\u092c\u0915\u093c\u0924-\u090f-\u0928\u0938\u0940\u0930\u0940' \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u0947\u0916\u0915 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Amir Khusro", "option2": "Shams i Siraj Afif", "option3": "Minhaj-i-Siraj", "option4": "Ibn Batuta", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:47:00+00:00", "question": "Who has composed 'Chandayan'?\n'\u091a\u0902\u0926\u093e\u092f\u0928' \u0915\u0940 \u0930\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Amor Khusro", "option2": "Damodar Kavi", "option3": "Mulla Daud", "option4": "Hafiz Shirazi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:47:00+00:00", "question": "What was 'Desai' in medieval India?\n\u092e\u0927\u094d\u092f\u0915\u093e\u0932\u0940\u0928 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 '\u0926\u0947\u0938\u093e\u0908 \u2019\u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Copper coin", "option2": "Type of tax", "option3": "Administrative title", "option4": "Length measurement unit", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:47:00+00:00", "question": "Which of the following temple is known as  'Khajuraho of Vidarbha'?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0930 \u0915\u094b '\u0935\u093f\u0926\u0930\u094d\u092d \u0915\u0947 \u0916\u091c\u0941\u0930\u093e\u0939\u094b' \u0915\u0947 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u091c\u093e\u0928\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Kailash temple", "option2": "Markandeshwar temple", "option3": "Bhimashankar temple", "option4": "Manudevi temple", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:05:04+00:00", "question": "'Sri Kailash' mountain is situated in which of the following state?\n'\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u0948\u0932\u093e\u0936' \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ladakh", "option2": "Himachal Pradesh", "option3": "Uttarakhand", "option4": "Arunachal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:05:04+00:00", "question": "'Saramati peak'  located in which of the following state?\n'\u0938\u093e\u0930\u093e\u092e\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Sikkim", "option2": "Mizoram", "option3": "Nagaland", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:05:04+00:00", "question": "Which is the highest peak of 'Arakan Mountain Range'?\nAn '\u0905\u0930\u093e\u0915\u093e\u0928 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0936\u094d\u0930\u0943\u0902\u0916\u0932\u093e\u2019 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u094b\u091a\u094d\u091a \u0936\u093f\u0916\u0930 \u0915\u094c\u0928-\u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mount Saramati", "option2": "Mount Victoria", "option3": "Sosogad peak", "option4": "Hkakabo Razi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:05:04+00:00", "question": "'Hardeol' peak is a part of which himalayan range?\n'\u0939\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094b\u0932 \u2019 \u0936\u093f\u0916\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0939\u093f\u092e\u093e\u0932\u092f\u0940 \u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0923\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0939\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Karakoram range", "option2": "Zaskar range", "option3": "Kumaon range", "option4": "Shivalik ranges", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:05:04+00:00", "question": "'Saser Kangri' mountain is located in which of the following state/ Union territories?\n'\u0938\u0947\u091c\u0930 \u0915\u093e\u0902\u0917\u0930\u0940' \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f/ \u0915\u0947\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930 \u0936\u093e\u0938\u093f\u0924 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ladakh", "option2": "Jammu and Kashmir", "option3": "Himachal Pradesh", "option4": "Uttarakhand", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:20+00:00", "question": "The 'Karoo Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0942 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928\u2019 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "North America", "option3": "Asia", "option4": "Africa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:20+00:00", "question": "The 'Mojave Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u092e\u094b\u091c\u093e\u0935\u0947 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "Africa", "option3": "South America", "option4": "North America", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:20+00:00", "question": "The 'Sturt Stony Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0930\u094d\u091f \u0938\u094d\u091f\u094b\u0928\u0940 \u0921\u0947\u091c\u0930\u094d\u091f' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "North America", "option3": "Antarctica", "option4": "Africa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:20+00:00", "question": "The 'Sonoran Desert' is situated in which continent?\nThe '\u0938\u094b\u0928\u094b\u0930\u093e\u0928 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928\u2019 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "North America", "option2": "South America", "option3": "Africa", "option4": "Australia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:20+00:00", "question": "The 'Tanami Desert' is situated in which continent?\nThe '\u0924\u0928\u093e\u092e\u0940 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "South America", "option2": "Africa", "option3": "Australia", "option4": "Asia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:43+00:00", "question": "Which of the following Indian states share shortest border with Bangladesh?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0917\u094d\u0932\u093e\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u093e\u0925 \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u0915\u092e \u0938\u0940\u092e\u093e \u0938\u093e\u091d\u093e \u0915\u0930\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mizoram", "option2": "Meghalaya", "option3": "Assam", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:43+00:00", "question": "What was the theme for 2020 International Mother Language Day?\n2020 \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092e\u093e\u0924\u0943\u092d\u093e\u0937\u093e \u0926\u093f\u0935\u0938 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0935\u093f\u0937\u092f \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Languages without borders", "option2": "Mother language", "option3": "Bonding by language", "option4": "Language and institutions", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:43+00:00", "question": "'Dabir ul Mulk' title to Mirza Ghalib bestowed by whom?\n\u092e\u093f\u0930\u094d\u091c\u093c\u093e \u0917\u093c\u093e\u0932\u093f\u092c \u0915\u094b '\u0926\u092c\u0940\u0930 \u0909\u0932 \u092e\u0941\u0932\u094d\u0915' \u0915\u093e \u0916\u093f\u0924\u093e\u092c \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0926\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Muhammad Shah", "option2": "Shah Alam II", "option3": "Bahadur Shah Zafar II", "option4": "Akbar Shah II", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:43+00:00", "question": "What was the theme of 3rd\u00a0Global Ministerial Conference on Road Safety held in Stockholm (Sweden)?\n\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0949\u0915\u0939\u094b\u092e (\u0938\u094d\u0935\u0940\u0921\u0928) \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0906\u092f\u094b\u091c\u093f\u0924 \u0938\u0921\u093c\u0915 \u0938\u0941\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u092a\u0930 \u0924\u0940\u0938\u0930\u0947 \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0938\u092e\u094d\u092e\u0947\u0932\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0937\u092f \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Risk management on road", "option2": "Caring for Future generations on road", "option3": "Achieving Global Objectives 2025", "option4": "Achieving Global Goals 2030", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:43+00:00", "question": "Someshwari and Jinjiram river lies in which of the following Indian state? \n\u0938\u094b\u092e\u0947\u0936\u094d\u0935\u0930\u0940 \u0914\u0930 \u091c\u093f\u0902\u091c\u0940\u0930\u093e\u092e \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Manipur", "option2": "Meghalaya", "option3": "Arunachal Pradesh", "option4": "Bihar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:02:02+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0'Global Risks Report'\u00a0is annual published by whom?\n'\u0917\u094d\u0932\u094b\u092c\u0932 \u0930\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0915 \u0930\u093f\u092a\u094b\u0930\u094d\u091f' \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0936\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Asian Development Bank", "option2": "International Monetary Fund", "option3": "World Bank", "option4": "World Economic Forum\u00a0", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:02:02+00:00", "question": "Newspaper 'Sambad Kaumudi' was founded by whom?\n\u0938\u092e\u093e\u091a\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0930 '\u0938\u092e\u094d\u092c\u093e\u0926 \u0915\u094c\u092e\u0941\u0926\u0940' \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093e\u092a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Devendra Nath Tagore", "option2": "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar", "option3": "Raja Ram Mohan Roy", "option4": "Bhagat Singh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:02:02+00:00", "question": "Which law commission has recently been approved by Union Cabinet?\n\u0939\u093e\u0932 \u0939\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u0947\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093f\u092e\u0902\u0921\u0932 \u0928\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u093f\u0927\u093f \u0906\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0915\u094b \u092e\u0902\u091c\u0942\u0930\u0940 \u0926\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "18th", "option2": "20th", "option3": "22nd", "option4": "24th", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:02:02+00:00", "question": "Who launched the\u00a0second phase of Swachh Bharat Mission (Grameen)\u00a0\n\u0938\u094d\u0935\u091a\u094d\u091b \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u093f\u0936\u0928 (\u0917\u094d\u0930\u093e\u092e\u0940\u0923) \u0915\u0947 \u0926\u0942\u0938\u0930\u0947 \u091a\u0930\u0923 \u0915\u093e \u0936\u0941\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092d \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e", "option1": "PM Narendra Modi", "option2": "Jal Shakti minister Gajendra Singh Shekhawat", "option3": "Minister of Rural Development\u00a0Narendra Singh Tomar", "option4": "Finance Minister\u00a0Nirmala Sitharaman", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:02:02+00:00", "question": "The Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana (PMFBY) was launched on\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0927\u093e\u0928\u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u092b\u0938\u0932 \u092c\u0940\u092e\u093e \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0936\u0941\u0930\u0942 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908", "option1": "2015", "option2": "2016", "option3": "2018", "option4": "2019", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:24:02+00:00", "question": "Who won best actor award for Dadasaheb Phalke International Film Festival Awards 2020?\n\u0926\u093e\u0926\u093e \u0938\u093e\u0939\u092c \u092b\u093e\u0932\u094d\u0915\u0947 \u0907\u0902\u091f\u0930\u0928\u0947\u0936\u0928\u0932 \u092b\u093f\u0932\u094d\u092e \u092b\u0947\u0938\u094d\u091f\u093f\u0935\u0932 \u0905\u0935\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094d\u0938 2020 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u091c\u0940\u0924\u093e?", "option1": "Hrithik Roshan", "option2": "Kiccha Sudeep", "option3": "Ranveer Singh", "option4": "Ayushmann Khurrana", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:24:02+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0best actress for Academy Award 2020 (Oscars) bagged by?\n\u0905\u0915\u093e\u0926\u092e\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 2020 (\u0911\u0938\u094d\u0915\u0930) \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0932\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Frances McDormand", "option2": "Olivia Colman", "option3": "Renee Zellweger", "option4": "Laura Dern", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:24:02+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0best actor for Academy Award 2020 (Oscar) bagged by?\n\u0905\u0915\u093e\u0926\u092e\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 2020 (\u0911\u0938\u094d\u0915\u0930) \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0932\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Gary Oldman", "option2": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "option3": "Brad Pitt", "option4": "Joaquin Phoenix", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:24:02+00:00", "question": "Which sportsman won the Laureus world sports award of the year 2020?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0916\u093f\u0932\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0928\u0947 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 2020 \u0915\u093e \u0932\u0949\u0930\u093f\u092f\u0938 \u0935\u093f\u0936\u094d\u0935 \u0916\u0947\u0932 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u091c\u0940\u0924\u093e?", "option1": "Lionel Messi & Lewis Hamilton", "option2": "Novak Djokovic", "option3": "Roger Federer", "option4": "Usain Bolt", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:24:02+00:00", "question": "International Gandhi Awards\u00a0for Leprosy\u00a02020 were presented to\n\u0932\u0947\u092a\u094d\u0930\u094b\u0938\u0940 2020 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0927\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0926\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093f\u090f \u0917\u090f", "option1": "Chandi Prasad Bhatt", "option2": "Julius Nyerere", "option3": "Dr N.S. Dharmashaktu", "option4": "Yohei Sasakawa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:17:37+00:00", "question": "Which river is known as 'Nila' ?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0915\u094b '\u0928\u0940\u0932\u093e' \u0915\u0947 \u0928\u093e\u092e \u0938\u0947 \u091c\u093e\u0928\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Palar", "option2": "Bharathappuzha", "option3": "Sharavati", "option4": "Periyar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:17:37+00:00", "question": "Palar river which confluence into bay of bengal having its origin from which of the following state?\n\u092a\u0932\u093e\u0930 \u0928\u0926\u0940, \u091c\u094b \u0915\u093f \u092c\u0947\u0902\u0917\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0916\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092e\u093f\u0932\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948, \u0907\u0938\u0915\u0940 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u092a\u0924\u094d\u0924\u093f \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0938\u0947 \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Odisha", "option2": "West Bengal", "option3": "Karnataka", "option4": "Kerala", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:03:11+00:00", "question": "What is Automatic Exchange of Information (AEOI) ?\n\u0938\u0942\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0938\u094d\u0935\u091a\u093e\u0932\u093f\u0924 \u0935\u093f\u0928\u093f\u092e\u092f (AEOI) \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "It aims to reduce global tax evasion. \u0907\u0938\u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u094d\u0926\u0947\u0936\u094d\u092f \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u0915\u0930 \u091a\u094b\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u094b \u0915\u092e \u0915\u0930\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option2": "It aims to curb political financing.\u0907\u0938\u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u094d\u0926\u0947\u0936\u094d\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u0928\u0940\u0924\u093f\u0915 \u0935\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0924\u092a\u094b\u0937\u0923 \u092a\u0930 \u0905\u0902\u0915\u0941\u0936 \u0932\u0917\u093e\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option3": "It is Indian government public welfare scheme.\u092f\u0939 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0938\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u094b\u0915 \u0915\u0932\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0923\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option4": "It is FATF initiative for information exchange.\u092f\u0939 \u0938\u0942\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0928\u093f\u092e\u092f \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u090f\u092b\u090f\u091f\u0940\u090f\u092b \u092a\u0939\u0932 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 15:40:24+00:00", "question": "System of Air Quality and Weather Forecasting and Research (SAFAR) was indigenously\u00a0developed by\n\u090f\u092f\u0930 \u0915\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0932\u093f\u091f\u0940 \u090f\u0902\u0921 \u0935\u0947\u0926\u0930 \u092b\u094b\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0938\u094d\u091f\u093f\u0902\u0917 \u090f\u0902\u0921 \u0930\u093f\u0938\u0930\u094d\u091a (SAFAR) \u0915\u0940 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0923\u093e\u0932\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0935\u0926\u0947\u0936\u0940 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u0938\u0947 \u0935\u093f\u0915\u0938\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908", "option1": "Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology, Pune.\u00a0", "option2": "Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur", "option3": "Indian Institute of Technology, Madras", "option4": "Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 15:40:24+00:00", "question": "Which of the following statements regarding Arjuna award is/are correct:-\n\u0905\u0930\u094d\u091c\u0941\u0928 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0915\u0925\u0928 \u0938\u0939\u0940 \u0939\u0948: -", "option1": "Arjuna award was started in 1965", "option2": "A cash price of 5 lakh is given to Arjun Awardee", "option3": "A sportsperson at the international level having consistent performance in last 4 years are eligible", "option4": "In 2019 Ravindra Jadeja and Poonam Yadav receive this award for cricket", "option5": "1 & 2", "option6": "1, 2 & 4", "option7": "3 & 4", "option8": "2, 3 & 4", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:54:55+00:00", "question": "When did Financial Action Task Force (FATF) expanded its authority to terrorism financing?\n\u092b\u093e\u0907\u0928\u0947\u0902\u0936\u093f\u092f\u0932 \u090f\u0915\u094d\u0936\u0928 \u091f\u093e\u0938\u094d\u0915 \u092b\u094b\u0930\u094d\u0938 (FATF) \u0928\u0947 \u0906\u0924\u0902\u0915\u0935\u093e\u0926 \u0935\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0924\u092a\u094b\u0937\u0923 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0905\u092a\u0928\u0947 \u0905\u0927\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u092c \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "1989", "option2": "1995", "option3": "2001", "option4": "2008", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:54:55+00:00", "question": "The Organisation for Economic co-operation and Development (OECD) is an intergovernmental economic organisation of ______ .\n\u0906\u0930\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0939\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0914\u0930 \u0935\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0938 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u0920\u0928 (OECD) ______ \u0915\u093e \u090f\u0915 \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930 \u0938\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u0906\u0930\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u0920\u0928 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option1": "Poor countries", "option2": "low income countries", "option3": "middle income countries", "option4": "high income countries", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:54:55+00:00", "question": "The Servants of India Society was formed by Gopal Krishna Gokhale in Pune in the year ____ .\n\u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u091f\u094d\u0938 \u0911\u092b \u0907\u0902\u0921\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0938\u094b\u0938\u093e\u0907\u091f\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0917\u0920\u0928 \u0917\u094b\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u0943\u0937\u094d\u0923 \u0917\u094b\u0916\u0932\u0947 \u0928\u0947 \u092a\u0941\u0923\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 ____ \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e\u0964", "option1": "1901", "option2": "1903", "option3": "1905", "option4": "1907", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:54:55+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0State\u00a0of\u00a0India's Birds\u00a02020\u00a0Report\u00a0was released\u00a0by ______ .\n\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u091f \u0911\u092b\u093c \u0907\u0902\u0921\u093f\u092f\u093e\u091c\u093c \u092c\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094d\u0938 2020 \u0930\u093f\u092a\u094b\u0930\u094d\u091f ______ \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940", "option1": "Animal Welfare Board of India", "option2": "13th\u00a0COP Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species of Wild Animals", "option3": "Wildlife Crime Control Bureau", "option4": "IUCN", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 05:26:38+00:00", "question": "Global Multidimensional Poverty index is released by UNDP is collaboration with \n\n \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u092c\u0939\u0941\u0906\u092f\u093e\u092e\u0940 \u0917\u0930\u0940\u092c\u0940 \u0938\u0942\u091a\u0915\u093e\u0902\u0915 2020 \u092f\u0942\u090f\u0928\u0921\u0940\u092a\u0940 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0930\u0940   \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0939\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0938\u0947", "option1": "Lancet\u0932\u0948\u0902\u0938\u0947\u091f", "option2": "Greenpeace\u0917\u094d\u0930\u0940\u0928\u092a\u0940\u0938", "option3": "Economic freedom Journal\u0906\u0930\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u094d\u0935\u0924\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0924\u093e \u091c\u0930\u094d\u0928\u0932", "option4": "Oxfam poverty and Human development initiative\u0911\u0915\u094d\u0938\u092b\u0948\u092e \u0917\u0930\u0940\u092c\u0940 \u0914\u0930 \u092e\u093e\u0928\u0935 \u0935\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0938 \u092a\u0939\u0932", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 05:26:38+00:00", "question": "Article 161 of the Indian Constitution is related to\n\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0938\u0902\u0935\u093f\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0905\u0928\u0941\u091a\u094d\u091b\u0947\u0926 161 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Inter state dispute\u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930\u094d\u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u0940\u092f \u0935\u093f\u0935\u093e\u0926", "option2": "Inter state relations\u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927", "option3": "Pardoning power of governor\u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u092e\u093e \u0936\u0915\u094d\u0924\u093f", "option4": "Salary and oath of governor.\u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u093e \u0935\u0947\u0924\u0928 \u0914\u0930 \u0936\u092a\u0925\u0964", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 05:26:38+00:00", "question": "What is correct with respect to Hagia Sophia?\n1. It is situated in Turkey's capital Ankara.\n2. It is UNESCO heritage site. \u0939\u093e\u0917\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0938\u094b\u092b\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0938\u0939\u0940 \u0939\u0948?  1. \u092f\u0939 \u0924\u0941\u0930\u094d\u0915\u0940 \u0915\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u0927\u093e\u0928\u0940 \u0905\u0902\u0915\u093e\u0930\u093e \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948\u0964  2. \u092f\u0939 \u092f\u0942\u0928\u0947\u0938\u094d\u0915\u094b \u0915\u0940 \u0927\u0930\u094b\u0939\u0930 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option1": "Only 1", "option2": "Only 2", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 04:58:48+00:00", "question": "The perform achieve and trade is a flagship Programme of \n\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0926\u0930\u094d\u0936\u0928, \u0939\u093e\u0938\u093f\u0932 \u0914\u0930 \u0935\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092a\u093e\u0930, \u090f\u0915 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u092e\u0941\u0916 \u0915\u093e\u0930\u094d\u092f\u0915\u094d\u0930\u092e \u0939\u0948", "option1": "NITI aayog", "option2": "Bureau of Energy Efficiency\u090a\u0930\u094d\u091c\u093e \u0926\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0924\u093e \u092c\u094d\u092f\u0942\u0930\u094b", "option3": "Ministry of Commerce and Industry\u0935\u093e\u0923\u093f\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0914\u0930 \u0909\u0926\u094d\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0932\u092f", "option4": "Ministry of science and technology\u0935\u093f\u091c\u094d\u091e\u093e\u0928 \u0914\u0930 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u094c\u0926\u094d\u092f\u094b\u0917\u093f\u0915\u0940 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0932\u092f", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 04:58:48+00:00", "question": "Farzad-B a known oil field is located in \n\n\u092b\u0930\u091c\u093c\u093e\u0926-\u092c\u0940 \u090f\u0915 \u091c\u094d\u091e\u093e\u0924 \u0924\u0947\u0932 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Iraq\u0907\u0930\u093e\u0915", "option2": "Iran\u0908\u0930\u093e\u0928", "option3": "Syria\u0938\u0940\u0930\u093f\u092f\u093e", "option4": "Saudi Arabia\u0938\u090a\u0926\u0940 \u0905\u0930\u092c", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 04:58:48+00:00", "question": "Kihoto Hollohan case is related with \n\nKihoto Hollohan \u0915\u0947\u0938 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Criminal Reforms\u0906\u092a\u0930\u093e\u0927\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0941\u0927\u093e\u0930", "option2": "Judicial reforms \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0941\u0927\u093e\u0930", "option3": "Judicial review in anti defection law \u0926\u0932\u092c\u0926\u0932 \u0935\u093f\u0930\u094b\u0927\u0940 \u0915\u093e\u0928\u0942\u0928 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u092e\u0940\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e", "option4": "Financial Bankruptcy\u0935\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0926\u093f\u0935\u093e\u0932\u093e", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 10:16:50+00:00", "question": "The Kailasa Temple located in Ellora is well known and notable for its \n\n\u090f\u0932\u094b\u0930\u093e \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u0948\u0932\u093e\u0938\u093e \u092e\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0930 \u0907\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0938\u093f\u0926\u094d\u0927 \u0914\u0930 \u0909\u0932\u094d\u0932\u0947\u0916\u0928\u0940\u092f \u0939\u0948 ", "option1": "Monolithic vertical excavation \u0905\u0916\u0902\u0921 \u090a\u0930\u094d\u0927\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0927\u0930 \u0916\u0941\u0926\u093e\u0908", "option2": "Highly erected shikharas and entry gates\u0905\u0924\u094d\u092f\u0927\u093f\u0915 \u0936\u093f\u0916\u0930 \u0914\u0930 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0935\u0947\u0936 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930 \u092c\u0928\u093e\u090f \u0917\u090f", "option3": "Peculiar construction style of garbhagrihas\u0917\u0921\u093c\u0917\u0921\u093c\u0940\u0939\u093e\u0938 \u0915\u0940 \u0905\u091c\u0940\u092c\u094b\u0917\u0930\u0940\u092c \u0928\u093f\u0930\u094d\u092e\u093e\u0923 \u0936\u0948\u0932\u0940", "option4": "Use of sandstone and limestone\u092c\u0932\u0941\u0906 \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0925\u0930 \u0914\u0930 \u091a\u0942\u0928\u093e \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0925\u0930 \u0915\u093e \u0909\u092a\u092f\u094b\u0917", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 10:16:50+00:00", "question": "Unusually high tides occur when \n\n\u0905\u0938\u093e\u092e\u093e\u0928\u094d\u092f \u0930\u0942\u092a \u0938\u0947 \u0909\u091a\u094d\u091a \u091c\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930 \u0924\u092c \u0939\u094b\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948 ", "option1": "earth is closest to both Sun and Moon \u092a\u0943\u0925\u094d\u0935\u0940 \u0938\u0942\u0930\u094d\u092f \u0914\u0930 \u091a\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930\u092e\u093e \u0926\u094b\u0928\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u0915\u0930\u0940\u092c \u0939\u0948", "option2": "earth is at a right angle between the Sun and Moon\u092a\u0943\u0925\u094d\u0935\u0940 \u0938\u0942\u0930\u094d\u092f \u0914\u0930 \u091a\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930\u092e\u093e \u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u090f\u0915 \u0938\u092e\u0915\u094b\u0923 \u092a\u0930 \u0939\u0948", "option3": "earth is between the Sun and Moon \u092a\u0943\u0925\u094d\u0935\u0940 \u0938\u0942\u0930\u094d\u092f \u0914\u0930 \u091a\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930\u092e\u093e \u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u0939\u0948", "option4": "None of the above is correct.\u0909\u092a\u0930\u094b\u0915\u094d\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094b\u0908 \u092d\u0940 \u0938\u0939\u0940 \u0928\u0939\u0940\u0902 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 10:16:50+00:00", "question": "A novel Bandi jivan was written by\n\n\u090f\u0915 \u0909\u092a\u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0938 \u092c\u0902\u0926\u0940 \u091c\u0940\u0935\u0928 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0932\u093f\u0916\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e", "option1": "Rasbehari Ghosh \u0930\u093e\u0938\u092c\u0947\u0939\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u0918\u094b\u0937", "option2": "Sachin Sanyal\u0938\u091a\u093f\u0928 \u0938\u093e\u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0932", "option3": "Jatin Bagha\u091c\u0924\u093f\u0928 \u092c\u093e\u0918\u093e", "option4": "Lala Hardayal\u0932\u093e\u0932\u093e \u0939\u0930\u0926\u092f\u093e\u0932", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 10:16:50+00:00", "question": "Indian Opinion a paper started by M. K. Gandhi during \n\n\u0907\u0902\u0921\u093f\u092f\u0928 \u0913\u092a\u093f\u0928\u093f\u092f\u0928 \u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094c\u0930\u093e\u0928 \u090f\u092e\u0964 \u0915\u0947\u0964 \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0927\u0940 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0936\u0941\u0930\u0942 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u090f\u0915 \u092a\u0947\u092a\u0930", "option1": "His stay at Africa during moderate phase 1894-1906\u0909\u0928\u0915\u093e \u0905\u092b\u094d\u0930\u0940\u0915\u093e \u092e\u0947\u0902\u092e\u0927\u094d\u092f\u092e \u091a\u0930\u0923 \u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094c\u0930\u093e\u0928  \u0930\u0939\u0928\u093e 1894-1906", "option2": "Satyagraha Phase of 1906-1914, 1906-1914 \u0915\u093e  \u0938\u0924\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0917\u094d\u0930\u0939 \u091a\u0930\u0923", "option3": "Non cooperation Movement 1920\u0905\u0938\u0939\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0906\u0902\u0926\u094b\u0932\u0928 1920", "option4": "Civil disobedience movement1930-31\u0938\u0935\u093f\u0928\u092f \u0905\u0935\u091c\u094d\u091e\u093e \u0906\u0902\u0926\u094b\u0932\u0928 1930-31", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 10:16:50+00:00", "question": "The first women to address the Indian National Congress Session \n\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f\u0915\u093e\u0902\u0917\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0938 \u0938\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u0915\u094b \u0938\u0902\u092c\u094b\u0927\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u0930\u0928\u0947 \u0935\u093e\u0932\u0940 \u092a\u0939\u0932\u0940 \u092e\u0939\u093f\u0932\u093e", "option1": "Sarojini Naidu\u0938\u0930\u094b\u091c\u093f\u0928\u0940 \u0928\u093e\u092f\u0921\u0942", "option2": "Annie Besant\u090f\u0928\u0940 \u092c\u0947\u0938\u0947\u0902\u091f", "option3": "Harsimrat kaur\u0939\u0930\u0938\u093f\u092e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u094c\u0930", "option4": "Kadambini Ganguly\u0915\u093e\u0926\u0902\u092c\u093f\u0928\u0940 \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0917\u0941\u0932\u0940", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 06:58:48+00:00", "question": "Our team is Running separate Channels for Daily Quiz and News Analysis.\nDo you want us to merge Both the channels ?", "option1": "Yes", "option2": "No", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 15:30:25+00:00", "question": "Question - 19\n\nAnswer", "option1": "A", "option2": "B", "option3": "C", "option4": "D", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 15:15:04+00:00", "question": "Question - 18\n\nAnswer", "option1": "A", "option2": "B", "option3": "C", "option4": "D", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 15:02:06+00:00", "question": "Question - 17\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 07:10:20+00:00", "question": "Question - 16\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-20 06:28:52+00:00", "question": "Question - 15\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "2 and 3 only", "option4": "1 and 3 only", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 10:53:12+00:00", "question": "Question -14\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 10:33:43+00:00", "question": "Question - 13\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-19 09:43:23+00:00", "question": "Question - 12\n\nChoose the correct", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "3 only", "option4": "1, 2 and 3", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-18 15:17:41+00:00", "question": "Question -11\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:19:48+00:00", "question": "Question - 10\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "3 only", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:17:05+00:00", "question": "Question -09\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 and 2 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:14:05+00:00", "question": "Question  - 08\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "1 and 2 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:10:32+00:00", "question": "Question - 07\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:06:49+00:00", "question": "Question - 06\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 16:03:38+00:00", "question": "Question - 05\n\nAnswer", "option1": "A", "option2": "B", "option3": "C", "option4": "D", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 15:59:22+00:00", "question": "Question - 04\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 15:53:55+00:00", "question": "Question - 03\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 15:50:12+00:00", "question": "Question - 02\n\nAnswer", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 15:43:36+00:00", "question": "Question - 01\n\nAnswer", "option1": "A", "option2": "B", "option3": "C", "option4": "D", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-17 06:36:31+00:00", "question": "Question- 01\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-05 18:29:18+00:00", "question": "Question 2\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-05-05 17:41:00+00:00", "question": "Select the Incorrect option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-17 11:51:23+00:00", "question": "Select the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-17 11:18:29+00:00", "question": "'Jatropha' is plant of Latin America origin, which has gained its importance for", "option1": "Production Bio Jet fuel", "option2": "Protecting the crops from pest attack", "option3": "Making technical textile", "option4": "Protect the ecosystem from invasive alien plants", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-17 10:38:00+00:00", "question": "It is Located in the Shiwalik foothills of Punjab which is highly eco-sensitive. The site is of historic importance as the Indian and Chinese Prime Ministers formalized the \u201cFive Principles of Peaceful Coexistence\u201d there in 1954. \n\nSelect correct option", "option1": "Nangal wildlife sanctuary", "option2": "Keshopur-miani Community Reserve", "option3": "Beas Conservation Reserve", "option4": "Saman Bird sanctuary.", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-11 12:11:27+00:00", "question": "Question - 19 \n\n'ASKDISHA chatbot' launched to resolve queries of", "option1": "Railway passenger", "option2": "Student of higher studies", "option3": "Employee of hazard industry", "option4": "Women regarding sexual harassment at work", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-11 11:34:45+00:00", "question": "Question -18\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-11 11:06:04+00:00", "question": "Question -17\n\nSelect the incorrect option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "2 and 3 only", "option4": "All of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-07 16:18:11+00:00", "question": "Question - 16\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "2 only", "option2": "1 and 3 only", "option3": "2 and 3 only", "option4": "1 and 2 only", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-07 15:59:54+00:00", "question": "Question - 15 \n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "2 and 3 only", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-07 07:28:57+00:00", "question": "Question - 14\n\nSelect the correct option.", "option1": "1 and 3 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "3 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 14:52:43+00:00", "question": "'Elephant Bond', recently seen in news, is", "option1": "Long term Bond to fund infrastructure project only", "option2": "Short term Bond to create a fund to protect the elephant from railway tracks", "option3": "Long term Bond to invest in  Defence Sector", "option4": "It is issued by government to meet their fiscal deficit", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 14:21:09+00:00", "question": "State Energy Efficiency Index developed by", "option1": "Bureau of Energy Efficiency", "option2": "Ministry of Power", "option3": "Niti Aayog", "option4": "POWERGRID, a Maharatna Central Public Sector Enterprise", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 13:50:37+00:00", "question": "Question -13\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "All of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 12:01:52+00:00", "question": "Question - 12\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "2 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "All of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 10:34:41+00:00", "question": "Consider the following statement regarding 'integrated road accident database'\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "It will help both state and centre to comprehend information related to road accident", "option2": "It has been developed by Indian institute of technology, Madras and National informatics centre", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-06 10:04:46+00:00", "question": "Question - 11\n\n'Micropilling technique' is used for the first time in india, is used for", "option1": "Construction of bridge", "option2": "Manufacturing of technical textile", "option3": "Extracting mineral from mines without affecting environment", "option4": "It is used in automobile to reduce the pollution level by 95%", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 16:35:53+00:00", "question": "Question -10\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 3 only", "option3": "2 and 3 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 16:28:37+00:00", "question": "Question - 9\n\nSelect the Incorrect option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 16:17:27+00:00", "question": "Question - 8\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "2 and 3 only", "option2": "2, 3 and 4 only", "option3": "3 and 4 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 16:13:52+00:00", "question": "Question -7\n\nSelect correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 and 3 only", "option3": "1 and 3 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 16:03:25+00:00", "question": "Questions - 6\n\nSelect correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "1 and 2 only", "option3": "2 only", "option4": "All of these", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 09:55:24+00:00", "question": "Questions - 5\n\nGlobal Energy Transition Report is released by", "option1": "World Economic Forum", "option2": "World Band", "option3": "United Nation Environment Program", "option4": "OPEC", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 09:44:48+00:00", "question": "Questions - 4\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "Both", "option4": "None", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-04-03 09:34:25+00:00", "question": "Questions 3\n\nSelect the correct option", "option1": "1 only", "option2": "2 only", "option3": "3 and 4 only", "option4": "1 and 3 only", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 18:02:00+00:00", "question": "Meja Dam is situated in which of the following state?\n\u092e\u0947\u091c\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Uttar Pradesh", "option2": "Madhya Pradesh", "option3": "Rajasthan", "option4": "Gujarat", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 17:56:06+00:00", "question": "On which of the following river Tilaiya Dam is situated?\n\u0924\u093f\u0932\u0948\u092f\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mayurakshi River", "option2": "Subarnarekha River", "option3": "Mahanadi River", "option4": "Barakar River", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 17:51:25+00:00", "question": "Tehri Dam is situated at the confluence of which two rivers?\n\u091f\u093f\u0939\u0930\u0940 \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u0915\u093f\u0928 \u0926\u094b \u0928\u0926\u093f\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u092e \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Bhagirathi & Bhilanagana", "option2": "Bhagirathi & Alaknanda", "option3": "Alaknanda & Pindar", "option4": "Bhagirathi & Ghaghara", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 17:39:14+00:00", "question": "'Thein Dam' is situated on the river of\n'\u0925\u0940\u0928 \u0921\u0948\u092e' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Jhelum", "option2": "Ravi", "option3": "Chenab", "option4": "Satluj", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 17:33:13+00:00", "question": "Which one of the following dam is not situated on the river Chenab?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0927 \u091a\u093f\u0928\u093e\u092c \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0928\u0939\u0940\u0902 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Dul Hasti Dam", "option2": "Baglihar Dam", "option3": "Mangla Dam", "option4": "Salal Dam", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:33:37+00:00", "question": "The example of famous 'Charbagh gardens' in India is\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0938\u093f\u0926\u094d\u0927 '\u091a\u093e\u0930\u092c\u093e\u0917 \u0909\u0926\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u093e\u0939\u0930\u0923 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Rashtrapati Bhavan garden", "option2": "Shalimar Bagh\u00a0", "option3": "Taj Mahal", "option4": "National War Memorial in New Delhi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:24:24+00:00", "question": "Who is the only US president who have visited India twice while in office?\n\u0935\u0939 \u090f\u0915\u092e\u093e\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u0905\u092e\u0947\u0930\u093f\u0915\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u092a\u0924\u093f \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u0948 \u091c\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u092a\u0926 \u092a\u0930 \u0930\u0939\u0924\u0947 \u0939\u0941\u090f \u0926\u094b \u092c\u093e\u0930 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u093e \u0926\u094c\u0930\u093e \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Bill Clinton", "option2": "George Bush Junior", "option3": "Barack Obama", "option4": "Donald Trump", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:21:37+00:00", "question": "PM- Kisan (Kisan Samman Nidhi) Yojana effective from\n\u092a\u0940\u090f\u092e- \u0915\u093f\u0938\u093e\u0928 (\u0915\u093f\u0938\u093e\u0928 \u0938\u092e\u094d\u092e\u093e\u0928 \u0928\u093f\u0927\u0940) \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0915\u092c \u0938\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u092d\u093e\u0935\u0940", "option1": "01.01.2020", "option2": "01.12.2019", "option3": "01.12.2018", "option4": "05.05.2017", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 14:11:43+00:00", "question": "The stone chariot shrine at Hampi dedicated to whom?\n\u0939\u092e\u094d\u092a\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0925\u0930 \u0915\u093e \u0930\u0925 \u092e\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u094b \u0938\u092e\u0930\u094d\u092a\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Vishnu", "option2": "Garuda", "option3": "Mouse", "option4": "Shiva", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-20 12:38:01+00:00", "question": "Sardar Patel stadium is now the world's largest cricket stadium. What is its seating capacity?\n\u0938\u0930\u0926\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u091f\u0947\u0932 \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u0921\u093f\u092f\u092e \u0905\u092c \u0926\u0941\u0928\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0915\u094d\u0930\u093f\u0915\u0947\u091f \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u0921\u093f\u092f\u092e \u0939\u0948\u0964 \u0907\u0938\u0915\u0940 \u092c\u0948\u0920\u0928\u0947 \u0915\u0940 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u092e\u0924\u093e \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "90,000", "option2": "110,000", "option3": "130,000", "option4": "150,000", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:23:16+00:00", "question": "Which is the largest bay in the world in terms of area?\n\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930\u092b\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0926\u0943\u0937\u094d\u091f\u093f \u0938\u0947 \u0935\u093f\u0936\u094d\u0935 \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u0940 \u0916\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Hudson Bay", "option2": "San Francisco Bay", "option3": "Bay of Bengal", "option4": "Bay of Fundy", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:16:56+00:00", "question": "Boeing P-8 Poseidon aircraft is used for\n\u092c\u094b\u0907\u0902\u0917 \u092a\u0940 -8 \u092a\u094b\u0938\u093f\u0921\u0949\u0928 \u0935\u093f\u092e\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0907\u0938\u094d\u0924\u0947\u092e\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Anti Piracy", "option2": "Anti submarine warfare", "option3": "Heavy lift operations", "option4": "Rescue operation in disaster management", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 15:11:58+00:00", "question": "Who was referred to as Kerala Gandhi?\n\u0915\u0947\u0930\u0932 \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0927\u0940 \u0915\u0947 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0926\u0930\u094d\u092d\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Moyarath Sankaran", "option2": "Koyapalli Kelappan Nair", "option3": "K.R. Narayanan", "option4": "Mohammed Abdul Rahiman", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 14:58:16+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is known as India's easternmost tiger reserve?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0947 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092a\u0942\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0940 \u092c\u093e\u0918 \u0905\u092d\u092f\u093e\u0930\u0923\u094d\u092f \u0915\u0939\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Pakke Tiger Reserve", "option2": "Kamlang Tiger Reserve", "option3": "Nameri tiger reserve", "option4": "Namdapha Tiger Reserve", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 14:54:14+00:00", "question": "Which of the following is the northernmost city of Afghanistan?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0905\u092b\u0917\u093e\u0928\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u0924\u0930\u0940 \u0936\u0939\u0930 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mazari Sharif", "option2": "Kabul", "option3": "Jalalabad", "option4": "Kandahar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:28:35+00:00", "question": "Geological Survey of India\u00a0(GSI) was founded in the year\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u092d\u0942\u0935\u0948\u091c\u094d\u091e\u093e\u0928\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 (\u091c\u0940\u090f\u0938\u0906\u0908) \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093e\u092a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "1851", "option2": "1898", "option3": "1951", "option4": "1995", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:25:03+00:00", "question": "In which of the following national park five Rhinos were died from Suspected Anthrax Infection?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0909\u0926\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0928 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0917\u094d\u0927 \u090f\u0928\u094d\u0925\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0915\u094d\u0938 \u0938\u0902\u0915\u094d\u0930\u092e\u0923 \u0938\u0947 \u092a\u093e\u0902\u091a \u0917\u0948\u0902\u0921\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u092e\u0943\u0924\u094d\u092f\u0941 \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Kaziranga National Park", "option2": "Jaldapara National Park", "option3": "Orang National Park", "option4": "Manas National Park", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:18:02+00:00", "question": "Yakshagana is a\u00a0traditional theatre\u00a0form of\u00a0which state?\n\u092f\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0917\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0915\u093e \u092a\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092a\u0930\u093f\u0915 \u0930\u0902\u0917\u092e\u0902\u091a \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Tamil Nadu", "option2": "Kerala", "option3": "Karnataka", "option4": "Andhra Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:13:26+00:00", "question": "What is the IUCN Status\u00a0of\u00a0Hilsa fish?\n\u0939\u093f\u0932\u0938\u093e \u092e\u091b\u0932\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0906\u0908\u092f\u0942\u0938\u0940\u090f\u0928 \u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u091f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Extinct- \u0935\u093f\u0932\u0941\u092a\u094d\u0924", "option2": "Threatened Species \u0916\u0924\u0930\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902", "option3": "Near-threatened \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 \u092a\u0930 \u0928\u093f\u0930\u094d\u092d\u0930", "option4": "Least Concern \u0916\u0924\u0930\u0947 \u0938\u0947 \u092c\u093e\u0939\u0930", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 13:02:14+00:00", "question": "Which is the largest protected\u00a0wetland\u00a0of the country?\n\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u092c\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093f\u0924 \u0906\u0930\u094d\u0926\u094d\u0930\u092d\u0942\u092e\u093f \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ashtamudi Wetland", "option2": "East Kolkata Wetland", "option3": "Keoladeo National Park", "option4": "Sundarban Wetland", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:26:23+00:00", "question": "India contributes what percentage of the global biodiversity?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u091c\u0948\u0935 \u0935\u093f\u0935\u093f\u0927\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0924\u0928\u093e \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0924\u093f\u0936\u0924 \u092f\u094b\u0917\u0926\u093e\u0928 \u0926\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "4%", "option2": "8%", "option3": "12%", "option4": "14%", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:24:58+00:00", "question": "The Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species (CMS) or the Bonn Convention was signed on\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0935\u093e\u0938\u0940 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u091c\u093e\u0924\u093f \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0923 (\u0938\u0940\u090f\u092e\u090f\u0938) \u092f\u093e \u092c\u0949\u0928 \u0915\u0928\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u0936\u0928 \u092a\u0930 \u0915\u0928\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u0936\u0928 \u092a\u0930 \u0939\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u090f \u0917\u090f \u0925\u0947", "option1": "1975", "option2": "1979", "option3": "1983", "option4": "1987", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:23:34+00:00", "question": "'Sri Rama Sagar Project' is situated on the river of\n'\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u092e \u0938\u093e\u0917\u0930 \u092a\u0930\u093f\u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u092a\u0930 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Godavari", "option2": "Krishna", "option3": "Mahanadi", "option4": "Narmada", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:21:38+00:00", "question": "Kadam River is a tributary of\n\u0915\u0926\u092e \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0938\u0939\u093e\u092f\u0915 \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Godavari", "option2": "Krishna", "option3": "Mahanadi", "option4": "Kaveri", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-19 09:19:35+00:00", "question": "Kawal Tiger Reserve\u00a0is\u00a0situated in which of the following state?\n\u0915\u0935\u093e\u0932 \u091f\u093e\u0907\u0917\u0930 \u0930\u093f\u091c\u0930\u094d\u0935 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Odisha", "option3": "Telangana", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:51:16+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0National Social Assistance Programme\u00a0(NSAP) was launched on\n\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0938\u093e\u092e\u093e\u091c\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0939\u093e\u092f\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e\u0930\u094d\u092f\u0915\u094d\u0930\u092e (NSAP) \u0915\u093e \u0936\u0941\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092d \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e", "option1": "1990", "option2": "1993", "option3": "1995", "option4": "1999", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:47:17+00:00", "question": "The provisions of the sixth schedule of Indian Constitution are applicable in which of the following states?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0938\u0902\u0935\u093f\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u0940 \u091b\u0920\u0940 \u0905\u0928\u0941\u0938\u0942\u091a\u0940 \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0935\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0932\u093e\u0917\u0942 \u0939\u094b\u0924\u0947 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Assam", "option2": "Nagaland", "option3": "Sikkim", "option4": "Manipur", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:42:26+00:00", "question": "The first National Panchayati Raj Day was observed on\n\u092a\u0939\u0932\u093e \u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092a\u0902\u091a\u093e\u092f\u0924\u0940 \u0930\u093e\u091c \u0926\u093f\u0935\u0938 \u092e\u0928\u093e\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e", "option1": "24 April 2010", "option2": "24 April 2012", "option3": "24 April 2014", "option4": "24 April 2016", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:37:38+00:00", "question": "Who is the head of the Prime Minister's Office\u00a0(PMO)?\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u093e\u0930\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0932\u092f (PMO) \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u092e\u0941\u0916 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u094b\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Cabinet Secretary", "option2": "Principal Secretary", "option3": "Defence Secretary", "option4": "Prime Minister", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-17 16:28:57+00:00", "question": "Who was the first\u00a0Comptroller and Auditor General (CAG) of India?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0915\u0947 \u092a\u0939\u0932\u0947 \u0928\u093f\u092f\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0915 \u0914\u0930 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0932\u0947\u0916\u093e \u092a\u0930\u0940\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0915 (CAG) \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0925\u0947?", "option1": "Rajiv Mehrishi", "option2": "S. Ranganathan", "option3": "A. K. Chanda", "option4": "V. Narahari Rao", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:34:55+00:00", "question": "Which of the following article deals with the pardoning power of the governor?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0905\u0928\u0941\u091a\u094d\u091b\u0947\u0926 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u092e\u093e \u0936\u0915\u094d\u0924\u093f \u0938\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Article 160", "option2": "Article 161", "option3": "Article 165", "option4": "Article 172", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:25:36+00:00", "question": "Which of the following article defines that it is our fundamental duty to protect and improve the natural environment including forests, lakes, rivers and wild life?\n\u0928\u0926\u093f\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u0914\u0930 \u0935\u0928\u094d\u092f \u091c\u0940\u0935\u0928 \u0938\u0939\u093f\u0924 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0915\u0943\u0924\u093f\u0915 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0935\u0930\u0923 \u0915\u0940 \u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u0914\u0930 \u0938\u0941\u0927\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0930\u0928\u093e \u0939\u092e\u093e\u0930\u093e \u092e\u094c\u0932\u093f\u0915 \u0915\u0930\u094d\u0924\u0935\u094d\u092f \u0939\u0948", "option1": "Article 51A(c)\u00a0", "option2": "Article 51A(e)", "option3": "Article 51A(f)\u00a0", "option4": "Article 51A(g)", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:17:03+00:00", "question": "What was the strength of judges in Constitution bench\u00a0of the Supreme Court\u00a0in the famous Kesavananda Bharati\u00a0judgement?\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0938\u093f\u0926\u094d\u0927 \u0915\u0947\u0938\u0935\u093e\u0928\u0902\u0926 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940 \u092b\u0948\u0938\u0932\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u094b\u091a\u094d\u091a \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093e\u0932\u092f \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u0902\u0935\u093f\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u092a\u0940\u0920 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0928\u094d\u092f\u093e\u092f\u093e\u0927\u0940\u0936\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u0902\u0916\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "09", "option2": "11", "option3": "13", "option4": "15", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:11:44+00:00", "question": "In which of the following state 'Angami' tribe is found?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 '\u0905\u0902\u0917\u093e\u092e\u0940' \u091c\u0928\u091c\u093e\u0924\u093f \u092a\u093e\u0908 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Meghalaya", "option2": "Nagaland", "option3": "Assam", "option4": "West Bengal", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 17:07:18+00:00", "question": "In which of the following regions 'Santa Ana' winds flow?\n'\u0938\u093e\u0902\u0924\u093e \u090f\u0928\u093e' \u0939\u0935\u093e\u090f\u0901 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092c\u0939\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "California", "option2": "Japan", "option3": "Sudan", "option4": "Germany", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:52:40+00:00", "question": "'Matorral vegetation' is found in which of the following region?\n'\u092e\u0947\u0915\u094d\u091f\u094b\u0930\u0932 \u0935\u0928\u0938\u094d\u092a\u0924\u093f \u2019\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u093e\u0908 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mediterranean coast", "option2": "South Indian coast", "option3": "Chile", "option4": "Mexico", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:46:47+00:00", "question": "'Chaparral tea' is found in which of the following region?\n'\u091b\u093e\u092a\u0930\u093e\u0932 \u091a\u093e\u092f\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092a\u093e\u092f\u0940 \u091c\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "South Africa", "option2": "India", "option3": "Argentina", "option4": "California", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:38:40+00:00", "question": "Which ridge is called as Dolphin Ridge?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093f\u091c \u0915\u094b \u0921\u0949\u0932\u094d\u092b\u093f\u0928 \u0930\u093f\u091c \u0915\u0939\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Indian Ocean ridge", "option2": "Mid Atlantic ridge", "option3": "South Atlantic ridge", "option4": "None of the above", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:28:55+00:00", "question": "'Karnapura' coal field is situated in which of the following river valley?\n'\u0915\u0930\u094d\u0928\u093e\u092a\u0941\u0930\u093e' \u0915\u094b\u092f\u0932\u093e \u0915\u094d\u0937\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0918\u093e\u091f\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Son Valley", "option2": "Damodar Valley", "option3": "Godavari Valley", "option4": "Mahanadi Valley", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-16 10:23:39+00:00", "question": "Which of the following rivers passes through Jim Corbett National Park?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u0940 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u091c\u093f\u092e \u0915\u0949\u0930\u094d\u092c\u0947\u091f \u0928\u0947\u0936\u0928\u0932 \u092a\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0915 \u0938\u0947 \u0939\u094b\u0915\u0930 \u0917\u0941\u091c\u0930\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mandakini river", "option2": "Pindar river", "option3": "Ramganga river", "option4": "Dhauliganga river", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:05:08+00:00", "question": "The 'Loess Plateau' is situated in which of the following country?\n'\u0932\u094b\u090f\u0938 \u092a\u0920\u093e\u0930' \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0926\u0947\u0936 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mongolia", "option2": "China", "option3": "Vietnam", "option4": "Myanmar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 11:00:56+00:00", "question": "Which department monitors earthquakes and conducts seismological research?\n\u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0935\u093f\u092d\u093e\u0917 \u092d\u0942\u0915\u0902\u092a \u0915\u0940 \u0928\u093f\u0917\u0930\u093e\u0928\u0940 \u0914\u0930 \u092d\u0942\u0915\u0902\u092a\u0940\u092f \u0905\u0928\u0941\u0938\u0902\u0927\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u0930\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "National Centre for Seismology", "option2": "Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology", "option3": "National Center for Earth System Sciences", "option4": "Indian Tsunami Early Warning Centre", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 10:54:42+00:00", "question": "'Achanakmar Wildlife Sanctuary'\u00a0is situated in which of the following state?\n'\u0905\u091a\u0928\u0915\u092e\u093e\u0930 \u0935\u0928\u094d\u092f\u091c\u0940\u0935 \u0905\u092d\u092f\u093e\u0930\u0923\u094d\u092f\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Madhya Pradesh", "option2": "Bihar", "option3": "Chhattisgarh", "option4": "Himachal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 10:49:44+00:00", "question": "How many states are the Satpura hills spread?\n\u0938\u0924\u092a\u0941\u0921\u093c\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u092a\u0939\u093e\u0921\u093c\u093f\u092f\u093e\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0924\u0928\u0947 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092b\u0948\u0932\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "3", "option2": "4", "option3": "5", "option4": "2", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-15 10:44:35+00:00", "question": "'Moribund delta' is a subdivision of which of the following delta?\n'\u092e\u094b\u0930\u093f\u092c\u0902\u0921 \u0921\u0947\u0932\u094d\u091f\u093e' \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0921\u0947\u0932\u094d\u091f\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0909\u092a\u0916\u0902\u0921 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Krishna Godavari delta", "option2": "Mahanadi delta", "option3": "Bengal delta", "option4": "Cauvery delta", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:19:56+00:00", "question": "The Indian National Army (INA) Defence Committee which was constituted in the year 1945 headed by whom?\n\u0906\u091c\u093e\u0926 \u0939\u093f\u0902\u0926 \u092b\u094c\u091c (INA) \u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u0938\u092e\u093f\u0924\u093f \u0915\u093e \u0917\u0920\u0928 1945 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0928\u0947\u0924\u0943\u0924\u094d\u0935 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Asaf Ali", "option2": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "option3": "Bhulabhai Desai", "option4": "Rajendra Prasad", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 17:02:06+00:00", "question": "Poona Pact was signed in between whom?\n\u092a\u0942\u0928\u093e \u092a\u0948\u0915\u094d\u091f \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u0939\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0915\u094d\u0937\u0930\u093f\u0924 \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Gandhi & Ambedkr", "option2": "MM Malviya & Ambedkar", "option3": "Gandhi & MM Malviya", "option4": "Ambedkar & Lord Willington", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 16:49:07+00:00", "question": "Which of the following movement was led by Madari Pasi?\n\u092e\u0926\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u092a\u093e\u0938\u0940 \u0928\u0947 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0906\u0902\u0926\u094b\u0932\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0928\u0947\u0924\u0943\u0924\u094d\u0935 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Pabna", "option2": "Santhal", "option3": "Eka", "option4": "Tana Bhagat", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 16:28:37+00:00", "question": "'Battle of Jajau' (battle of succession of Aurangzeb) was fought in which of the following year?\n'\u091c\u093e\u091c\u090a \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908' (\u0914\u0930\u0902\u0917\u091c\u0947\u092c \u0915\u0947 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u0924\u0930\u093e\u0927\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908) \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "1706", "option2": "1707", "option3": "1708", "option4": "1710", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 16:23:49+00:00", "question": "Between whom the\u00a0battle of Dharmat\u00a0was fought?\n\u0927\u0930\u094d\u092e\u0924 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u0921\u093c\u093e\u0908 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u092c\u0940\u091a \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Jalal Khan & Banda Singh Bahadur", "option2": "Maratha empire & Mughal empire", "option3": "Aurangzeb & Sambhaji", "option4": "Dara Shikoh & Aurangzeb", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 14:42:53+00:00", "question": "Who was the\u00a0last\u00a0king of the\u00a0Pallava\u00a0dynasty?\n\u092a\u0932\u094d\u0932\u0935 \u0935\u0902\u0936 \u0915\u093e \u0905\u0902\u0924\u093f\u092e \u0930\u093e\u091c\u093e \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Aparajitavarman", "option2": "Dantivarman", "option3": "Mahendravarman II", "option4": "Nandivarman III", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 14:36:40+00:00", "question": "Who is the author of 'Tabaqat-i-Nasiri'?\n'\u0924\u092c\u0915\u093c\u0924-\u090f-\u0928\u0938\u0940\u0930\u0940' \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u0947\u0916\u0915 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0939\u0948\u0902?", "option1": "Amir Khusro", "option2": "Shams i Siraj Afif", "option3": "Minhaj-i-Siraj", "option4": "Ibn Batuta", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:46:49+00:00", "question": "Who has composed 'Chandayan'?\n'\u091a\u0902\u0926\u093e\u092f\u0928' \u0915\u0940 \u0930\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Amor Khusro", "option2": "Damodar Kavi", "option3": "Mulla Daud", "option4": "Hafiz Shirazi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:39:21+00:00", "question": "What was 'Desai' in medieval India?\n\u092e\u0927\u094d\u092f\u0915\u093e\u0932\u0940\u0928 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 '\u0926\u0947\u0938\u093e\u0908 \u2019\u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Copper coin", "option2": "Type of tax", "option3": "Administrative title", "option4": "Length measurement unit", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-14 12:34:06+00:00", "question": "Which of the following temple is known as  'Khajuraho of Vidarbha'?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0902\u0926\u093f\u0930 \u0915\u094b '\u0935\u093f\u0926\u0930\u094d\u092d \u0915\u0947 \u0916\u091c\u0941\u0930\u093e\u0939\u094b' \u0915\u0947 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u091c\u093e\u0928\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Kailash temple", "option2": "Markandeshwar temple", "option3": "Bhimashankar temple", "option4": "Manudevi temple", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:04:46+00:00", "question": "'Sri Kailash' mountain is situated in which of the following state?\n'\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u0948\u0932\u093e\u0936' \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ladakh", "option2": "Himachal Pradesh", "option3": "Uttarakhand", "option4": "Arunachal Pradesh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 16:00:31+00:00", "question": "'Saramati peak'  located in which of the following state?\n'\u0938\u093e\u0930\u093e\u092e\u093e\u0924\u0940 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924\u2019 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Sikkim", "option2": "Mizoram", "option3": "Nagaland", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 15:55:46+00:00", "question": "Which is the highest peak of 'Arakan Mountain Range'?\nAn '\u0905\u0930\u093e\u0915\u093e\u0928 \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0936\u094d\u0930\u0943\u0902\u0916\u0932\u093e\u2019 \u0915\u093e \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u094b\u091a\u094d\u091a \u0936\u093f\u0916\u0930 \u0915\u094c\u0928-\u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mount Saramati", "option2": "Mount Victoria", "option3": "Sosogad peak", "option4": "Hkakabo Razi", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 15:46:01+00:00", "question": "'Hardeol' peak is a part of which himalayan range?\n'\u0939\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094b\u0932 \u2019 \u0936\u093f\u0916\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0939\u093f\u092e\u093e\u0932\u092f\u0940 \u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0923\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0939\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0938\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Karakoram range", "option2": "Zaskar range", "option3": "Kumaon range", "option4": "Shivalik ranges", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-11 15:34:31+00:00", "question": "'Saser Kangri' mountain is located in which of the following state/ Union territories?\n'\u0938\u0947\u091c\u0930 \u0915\u093e\u0902\u0917\u0930\u0940' \u092a\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0924 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f/ \u0915\u0947\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930 \u0936\u093e\u0938\u093f\u0924 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Ladakh", "option2": "Jammu and Kashmir", "option3": "Himachal Pradesh", "option4": "Uttarakhand", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:18:02+00:00", "question": "The 'Karoo Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0942 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928\u2019 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "North America", "option3": "Asia", "option4": "Africa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:03:52+00:00", "question": "The 'Mojave Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u092e\u094b\u091c\u093e\u0935\u0947 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "Africa", "option3": "South America", "option4": "North America", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 06:00:45+00:00", "question": "The 'Sturt Stony Desert' is situated in which continent?\n'\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0930\u094d\u091f \u0938\u094d\u091f\u094b\u0928\u0940 \u0921\u0947\u091c\u0930\u094d\u091f' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Australia", "option2": "North America", "option3": "Antarctica", "option4": "Africa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 05:51:44+00:00", "question": "The 'Sonoran Desert' is situated in which continent?\nThe '\u0938\u094b\u0928\u094b\u0930\u093e\u0928 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928\u2019 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "North America", "option2": "South America", "option3": "Africa", "option4": "Australia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-10 05:49:02+00:00", "question": "The 'Tanami Desert' is situated in which continent?\nThe '\u0924\u0928\u093e\u092e\u0940 \u0930\u0947\u0917\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0928' \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092e\u0939\u093e\u0926\u094d\u0935\u0940\u092a \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "South America", "option2": "Africa", "option3": "Australia", "option4": "Asia", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 18:05:23+00:00", "question": "Which of the following Indian states share shortest border with Bangladesh?\n\u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092c\u093e\u0902\u0917\u094d\u0932\u093e\u0926\u0947\u0936 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u093e\u0925 \u0938\u092c\u0938\u0947 \u0915\u092e \u0938\u0940\u092e\u093e \u0938\u093e\u091d\u093e \u0915\u0930\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Mizoram", "option2": "Meghalaya", "option3": "Assam", "option4": "Tripura", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 17:59:00+00:00", "question": "What was the theme for 2020 International Mother Language Day?\n2020 \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092e\u093e\u0924\u0943\u092d\u093e\u0937\u093e \u0926\u093f\u0935\u0938 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0935\u093f\u0937\u092f \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Languages without borders", "option2": "Mother language", "option3": "Bonding by language", "option4": "Language and institutions", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 17:54:30+00:00", "question": "'Dabir ul Mulk' title to Mirza Ghalib bestowed by whom?\n\u092e\u093f\u0930\u094d\u091c\u093c\u093e \u0917\u093c\u093e\u0932\u093f\u092c \u0915\u094b '\u0926\u092c\u0940\u0930 \u0909\u0932 \u092e\u0941\u0932\u094d\u0915' \u0915\u093e \u0916\u093f\u0924\u093e\u092c \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0926\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Muhammad Shah", "option2": "Shah Alam II", "option3": "Bahadur Shah Zafar II", "option4": "Akbar Shah II", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 17:45:14+00:00", "question": "What was the theme of 3rd\u00a0Global Ministerial Conference on Road Safety held in Stockholm (Sweden)?\n\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0949\u0915\u0939\u094b\u092e (\u0938\u094d\u0935\u0940\u0921\u0928) \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0906\u092f\u094b\u091c\u093f\u0924 \u0938\u0921\u093c\u0915 \u0938\u0941\u0930\u0915\u094d\u0937\u093e \u092a\u0930 \u0924\u0940\u0938\u0930\u0947 \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0938\u092e\u094d\u092e\u0947\u0932\u0928 \u0915\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0937\u092f \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e?", "option1": "Risk management on road", "option2": "Caring for Future generations on road", "option3": "Achieving Global Objectives 2025", "option4": "Achieving Global Goals 2030", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 17:40:07+00:00", "question": "Someshwari and Jinjiram river lies in which of the following Indian state? \n\u0938\u094b\u092e\u0947\u0936\u094d\u0935\u0930\u0940 \u0914\u0930 \u091c\u093f\u0902\u091c\u0940\u0930\u093e\u092e \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0924 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Manipur", "option2": "Meghalaya", "option3": "Arunachal Pradesh", "option4": "Bihar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 10:01:43+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0'Global Risks Report'\u00a0is annual published by whom?\n'\u0917\u094d\u0932\u094b\u092c\u0932 \u0930\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0915 \u0930\u093f\u092a\u094b\u0930\u094d\u091f' \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0936\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Asian Development Bank", "option2": "International Monetary Fund", "option3": "World Bank", "option4": "World Economic Forum\u00a0", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 09:57:29+00:00", "question": "Newspaper 'Sambad Kaumudi' was founded by whom?\n\u0938\u092e\u093e\u091a\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u0924\u094d\u0930 '\u0938\u092e\u094d\u092c\u093e\u0926 \u0915\u094c\u092e\u0941\u0926\u0940' \u0915\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0925\u093e\u092a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940?", "option1": "Devendra Nath Tagore", "option2": "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar", "option3": "Raja Ram Mohan Roy", "option4": "Bhagat Singh", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 09:44:49+00:00", "question": "Which law commission has recently been approved by Union Cabinet?\n\u0939\u093e\u0932 \u0939\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u0947\u0902\u0926\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u093f\u092e\u0902\u0921\u0932 \u0928\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0935\u093f\u0927\u093f \u0906\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0915\u094b \u092e\u0902\u091c\u0942\u0930\u0940 \u0926\u0940 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "18th", "option2": "20th", "option3": "22nd", "option4": "24th", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 09:41:40+00:00", "question": "Who launched the\u00a0second phase of Swachh Bharat Mission (Grameen)\u00a0\n\u0938\u094d\u0935\u091a\u094d\u091b \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u092e\u093f\u0936\u0928 (\u0917\u094d\u0930\u093e\u092e\u0940\u0923) \u0915\u0947 \u0926\u0942\u0938\u0930\u0947 \u091a\u0930\u0923 \u0915\u093e \u0936\u0941\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0902\u092d \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e", "option1": "PM Narendra Modi", "option2": "Jal Shakti minister Gajendra Singh Shekhawat", "option3": "Minister of Rural Development\u00a0Narendra Singh Tomar", "option4": "Finance Minister\u00a0Nirmala Sitharaman", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-09 09:35:36+00:00", "question": "The Pradhan Mantri Fasal Bima Yojana (PMFBY) was launched on\n\u092a\u094d\u0930\u0927\u093e\u0928\u092e\u0902\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u092b\u0938\u0932 \u092c\u0940\u092e\u093e \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0936\u0941\u0930\u0942 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908", "option1": "2015", "option2": "2016", "option3": "2018", "option4": "2019", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:23:36+00:00", "question": "Who won best actor award for Dadasaheb Phalke International Film Festival Awards 2020?\n\u0926\u093e\u0926\u093e \u0938\u093e\u0939\u092c \u092b\u093e\u0932\u094d\u0915\u0947 \u0907\u0902\u091f\u0930\u0928\u0947\u0936\u0928\u0932 \u092b\u093f\u0932\u094d\u092e \u092b\u0947\u0938\u094d\u091f\u093f\u0935\u0932 \u0905\u0935\u093e\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094d\u0938 2020 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0928\u0947 \u091c\u0940\u0924\u093e?", "option1": "Hrithik Roshan", "option2": "Kiccha Sudeep", "option3": "Ranveer Singh", "option4": "Ayushmann Khurrana", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:16:24+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0best actress for Academy Award 2020 (Oscars) bagged by?\n\u0905\u0915\u093e\u0926\u092e\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 2020 (\u0911\u0938\u094d\u0915\u0930) \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u094d\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0932\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Frances McDormand", "option2": "Olivia Colman", "option3": "Renee Zellweger", "option4": "Laura Dern", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:13:21+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0best actor for Academy Award 2020 (Oscar) bagged by?\n\u0905\u0915\u093e\u0926\u092e\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 2020 (\u0911\u0938\u094d\u0915\u0930) \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0936\u094d\u0930\u0947\u0937\u094d\u0920 \u0905\u092d\u093f\u0928\u0947\u0924\u093e \u0915\u093e \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093f\u0938\u0915\u0947 \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u0932\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0917\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "Gary Oldman", "option2": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "option3": "Brad Pitt", "option4": "Joaquin Phoenix", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 16:05:32+00:00", "question": "Which sportsman won the Laureus world sports award of the year 2020?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0916\u093f\u0932\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u0928\u0947 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 2020 \u0915\u093e \u0932\u0949\u0930\u093f\u092f\u0938 \u0935\u093f\u0936\u094d\u0935 \u0916\u0947\u0932 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u091c\u0940\u0924\u093e?", "option1": "Lionel Messi & Lewis Hamilton", "option2": "Novak Djokovic", "option3": "Roger Federer", "option4": "Usain Bolt", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-03 15:57:48+00:00", "question": "International Gandhi Awards\u00a0for Leprosy\u00a02020 were presented to\n\u0932\u0947\u092a\u094d\u0930\u094b\u0938\u0940 2020 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930\u094d\u0930\u093e\u0937\u094d\u091f\u094d\u0930\u0940\u092f \u0917\u093e\u0902\u0927\u0940 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0926\u093e\u0928 \u0915\u093f\u090f \u0917\u090f", "option1": "Chandi Prasad Bhatt", "option2": "Julius Nyerere", "option3": "Dr N.S. Dharmashaktu", "option4": "Yohei Sasakawa", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:17:11+00:00", "question": "Which river is known as 'Nila' ?\n\u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0928\u0926\u0940 \u0915\u094b '\u0928\u0940\u0932\u093e' \u0915\u0947 \u0928\u093e\u092e \u0938\u0947 \u091c\u093e\u0928\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0924\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Palar", "option2": "Bharathappuzha", "option3": "Sharavati", "option4": "Periyar", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:12:53+00:00", "question": "Palar river which confluence into bay of bengal having its origin from which of the following state?\n\u092a\u0932\u093e\u0930 \u0928\u0926\u0940, \u091c\u094b \u0915\u093f \u092c\u0947\u0902\u0917\u0932 \u0915\u0940 \u0916\u093e\u0921\u093c\u0940 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u092e\u093f\u0932\u0924\u0940 \u0939\u0948, \u0907\u0938\u0915\u0940 \u0909\u0924\u094d\u092a\u0924\u094d\u0924\u093f \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u093f\u0938 \u0930\u093e\u091c\u094d\u092f \u0938\u0947 \u0939\u0941\u0908 \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "Odisha", "option2": "West Bengal", "option3": "Karnataka", "option4": "Kerala", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 16:01:37+00:00", "question": "What is Automatic Exchange of Information (AEOI) ?\n\u0938\u0942\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0915\u093e \u0938\u094d\u0935\u091a\u093e\u0932\u093f\u0924 \u0935\u093f\u0928\u093f\u092e\u092f (AEOI) \u0915\u094d\u092f\u093e \u0939\u0948?", "option1": "It aims to reduce global tax evasion. \u0907\u0938\u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u094d\u0926\u0947\u0936\u094d\u092f \u0935\u0948\u0936\u094d\u0935\u093f\u0915 \u0915\u0930 \u091a\u094b\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u094b \u0915\u092e \u0915\u0930\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option2": "It aims to curb political financing.\u0907\u0938\u0915\u093e \u0909\u0926\u094d\u0926\u0947\u0936\u094d\u092f \u0930\u093e\u091c\u0928\u0940\u0924\u093f\u0915 \u0935\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0924\u092a\u094b\u0937\u0923 \u092a\u0930 \u0905\u0902\u0915\u0941\u0936 \u0932\u0917\u093e\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option3": "It is Indian government public welfare scheme.\u092f\u0939 \u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924 \u0938\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0940 \u0932\u094b\u0915 \u0915\u0932\u094d\u092f\u093e\u0923\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u092f\u094b\u091c\u0928\u093e \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option4": "It is FATF initiative for information exchange.\u092f\u0939 \u0938\u0942\u091a\u0928\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0928\u093f\u092e\u092f \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u090f\u092b\u090f\u091f\u0940\u090f\u092b \u092a\u0939\u0932 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 15:40:13+00:00", "question": "System of Air Quality and Weather Forecasting and Research (SAFAR) was indigenously\u00a0developed by\n\u090f\u092f\u0930 \u0915\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0932\u093f\u091f\u0940 \u090f\u0902\u0921 \u0935\u0947\u0926\u0930 \u092b\u094b\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0938\u094d\u091f\u093f\u0902\u0917 \u090f\u0902\u0921 \u0930\u093f\u0938\u0930\u094d\u091a (SAFAR) \u0915\u0940 \u092a\u094d\u0930\u0923\u093e\u0932\u0940 \u0938\u094d\u0935\u0926\u0947\u0936\u0940 \u0930\u0942\u092a \u0938\u0947 \u0935\u093f\u0915\u0938\u093f\u0924 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908", "option1": "Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology, Pune.\u00a0", "option2": "Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur", "option3": "Indian Institute of Technology, Madras", "option4": "Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 15:20:51+00:00", "question": "Which of the following statements regarding Arjuna award is/are correct:-\n\u0905\u0930\u094d\u091c\u0941\u0928 \u092a\u0941\u0930\u0938\u094d\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u0947 \u0938\u0902\u092c\u0902\u0927 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0928\u093f\u092e\u094d\u0928\u0932\u093f\u0916\u093f\u0924 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0938\u0947 \u0915\u094c\u0928 \u0938\u093e \u0915\u0925\u0928 \u0938\u0939\u0940 \u0939\u0948: -", "option1": "Arjuna award was started in 1965", "option2": "A cash price of 5 lakh is given to Arjun Awardee", "option3": "A sportsperson at the international level having consistent performance in last 4 years are eligible", "option4": "In 2019 Ravindra Jadeja and Poonam Yadav receive this award for cricket", "option5": "1 & 2", "option6": "1, 2 & 4", "option7": "3 & 4", "option8": "2, 3 & 4", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:54:29+00:00", "question": "When did Financial Action Task Force (FATF) expanded its authority to terrorism financing?\n\u092b\u093e\u0907\u0928\u0947\u0902\u0936\u093f\u092f\u0932 \u090f\u0915\u094d\u0936\u0928 \u091f\u093e\u0938\u094d\u0915 \u092b\u094b\u0930\u094d\u0938 (FATF) \u0928\u0947 \u0906\u0924\u0902\u0915\u0935\u093e\u0926 \u0935\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0924\u092a\u094b\u0937\u0923 \u0915\u0947 \u0932\u093f\u090f \u0905\u092a\u0928\u0947 \u0905\u0927\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u093e \u0935\u093f\u0938\u094d\u0924\u093e\u0930 \u0915\u092c \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "1989", "option2": "1995", "option3": "2001", "option4": "2008", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:45:55+00:00", "question": "The Organisation for Economic co-operation and Development (OECD) is an intergovernmental economic organisation of ______ .\n\u0906\u0930\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0939\u092f\u094b\u0917 \u0914\u0930 \u0935\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0938 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u0920\u0928 (OECD) ______ \u0915\u093e \u090f\u0915 \u0905\u0902\u0924\u0930 \u0938\u0930\u0915\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u0906\u0930\u094d\u0925\u093f\u0915 \u0938\u0902\u0917\u0920\u0928 \u0939\u0948\u0964", "option1": "Poor countries", "option2": "low income countries", "option3": "middle income countries", "option4": "high income countries", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:34:42+00:00", "question": "The Servants of India Society was formed by Gopal Krishna Gokhale in Pune in the year ____ .\n\u0938\u0930\u094d\u0935\u0947\u0902\u091f\u094d\u0938 \u0911\u092b \u0907\u0902\u0921\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0938\u094b\u0938\u093e\u0907\u091f\u0940 \u0915\u093e \u0917\u0920\u0928 \u0917\u094b\u092a\u093e\u0932 \u0915\u0943\u0937\u094d\u0923 \u0917\u094b\u0916\u0932\u0947 \u0928\u0947 \u092a\u0941\u0923\u0947 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0935\u0930\u094d\u0937 ____ \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e \u0925\u093e\u0964", "option1": "1901", "option2": "1903", "option3": "1905", "option4": "1907", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:27:55+00:00", "question": "The\u00a0State\u00a0of\u00a0India's Birds\u00a02020\u00a0Report\u00a0was released\u00a0by ______ .\n\u0938\u094d\u091f\u0947\u091f \u0911\u092b\u093c \u0907\u0902\u0921\u093f\u092f\u093e\u091c\u093c \u092c\u0930\u094d\u0921\u094d\u0938 2020 \u0930\u093f\u092a\u094b\u0930\u094d\u091f ______ \u0926\u094d\u0935\u093e\u0930\u093e \u091c\u093e\u0930\u0940 \u0915\u0940 \u0917\u0908 \u0925\u0940", "option1": "Animal Welfare Board of India", "option2": "13th\u00a0COP Convention on the Conservation of Migratory Species of Wild Animals", "option3": "Wildlife Crime Control Bureau", "option4": "IUCN", "Answer": "No answer given"}, {"Date": "2020-07-02 11:17:19+00:00", "question": "When did the\u00a0Indian Army\u00a0began inducting women officers in non-medical roles?\n\u092d\u093e\u0930\u0924\u0940\u092f \u0938\u0947\u0928\u093e \u0928\u0947 \u092e\u0939\u093f\u0932\u093e \u0905\u0927\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0930\u093f\u092f\u094b\u0902 \u0915\u094b \u0917\u0948\u0930-\u091a\u093f\u0915\u093f\u0924\u094d\u0938\u093e \u092d\u0942\u092e\u093f\u0915\u093e\u0913\u0902 \u092e\u0947\u0902 \u0936\u093e\u092e\u093f\u0932 \u0915\u0930\u0928\u093e \u0915\u092c \u0936\u0941\u0930\u0942 \u0915\u093f\u092f\u093e?", "option1": "From 1989", "option2": "From 1990", "option3": "From 1992", "option4": "From 1995", "Answer": "No answer given"}]